Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Hello, good evening and good day
everybody wherever you are in the and
welcome to the 329th episode of the Ask
Abijit Show. I hope you're all doing
fantastic. You're all doing great and
I'm going to take questions as many as
possible as will be possible today from
the super chat. But before we do that,
as always, let's see who all is there on
the live on the live chat. I can see
Vihang Kurani Pratar Dana Adit Ashini
Tanesh Pandi Rajesh Daswani Real Vad
Putin General Subutai uh Putin 444
Nutan Roshan Geopolitical Dubai is here
from Indor D 1894
Tidesh Pande Abhinav Mishra Priyanchi
Sud Om Swami0709
Sam the gamer good to see you sir
geopolitical once again Duv Duya Duv
durya Omgupta India we live. Yes sir.
Sam the gamer. Kushbu art. Namaskar. Ita
1995.
Karab good evening. Nanitadas. Namaste.
John M. Funk. Hello. Soldier boy. Shri
Hari Arun Raki Ganwani Naganand Shinoi.
Dashan Patel Heisenberg O2J Jind Madav
Gupta Namaskar Tmed Pand once again GK
GK87 good morning
the from Alman from Germany
uh Gou Ram Ram Daval 2233 hello Dan Bil
wise idiot that's quite a name hello
Rohan buri good evening good evening
Jahind indeed Anish Ashish Chabra
namaste brown leprechaun from Ireland
well Good to have you. Brown Leprechaun,
good evening. Um, good afternoon,
evening I suppose. Uh, just some nut.
Namaste. Uh, DK, DJJ, Satabish, history
and poetry. Pranam, Swami is here from
Jaipur. Uh, who else? Sam Gamer, Ian
4107, Namaskar, Lutan, Roshan, Haggi,
Pranam, Random Skull, Jash Krishna, sir,
good to see you. Random skull, Dashan
Patil, Lucky Bharaj, Gou
AGF, Shiva, Madhav, Gupta, user 360, uh,
Iscon, Sam the Gamer, uh, Aayush Saraf,
hello Mac 4, J1U, namaskar, Crazy Brain,
hello, good to see you. Shrihari Ajun,
once again, Sumit Agarwal, Bonjour,
Manish, Namaste, ma'am. Sai Sai Nirup
from Hyderabad, Namaskar. and everybody
else. Abin of Mishra dashil uh Vikash PJ
meow soldier boy says meow.
Okay, who else? Mohidash namask namaste
from Odisha. Namaste indeed. Uh Shinh
Harun is here from Mumbai. Sharon Ga and
everybody else. Madagupant
Ram Ram Omar Omar Kumbar Raki Ganwani
uh Sujit Shanagora and everyone else is
here from Vashim Maharashtra. Good to
see you and say everybody say hello to
everybody in Vashim. Kahan is here from
Delhi and uh all right Swastik Mahesh
Hello Priyanka Jala good evening ma'am.
Amisha Mishra good evening ma'am. Vijay
Vagala Vagela good morning G good
morning to you and all right okay uh so
what's the questions that we have Raki
Raki Gmani says how do you deal with
haters and trollers on the internet why
do we need to deal with them ignore them
look if you are on the internet if you
are a known face on the internet you
will have some people who don't like you
that's just natural you can't expect
everybody to like you and that's fine
that's fine so there's going people be
people who are not big fans of me. Yeah,
there going to be some people who will
want to abuse and troll and all that.
Makes no difference to me. I have very
thick skin. It's okay. Those of those
who don't like me or don't agree with
me, please feel free to don't to
disagree. It's no no issue. You don't
have to agree. And those who abuse and
troll, well, let me just tell them makes
no difference to me whatsoever. It
doesn't uh
generally the people who abuse and
troll, it's okay to disagree, but when
you abuse and troll, you're trying to
bully someone and try to trying to make
them feel bad, trying to demoralize
them, trying to, you know, lower their
morale. Well, let me just inform them
all. It makes no difference to me
whatsoever. Nothing whatsoever. So, uh
yeah.
Okay. So, let's get going with the super
chats. Yeah. Honey Sharma says,
"Greetings." Well, greetings to you
indeed. Anishma Basar bandit says Piety
I hope yes I hope you said that if US
does regime change in Iran we might see
US boots on the ground in Pakistan
occupied Jammu Kashmir Gilgit but since
temporary nation is a vasal what stops
US boats in Kashmir right now well right
now actually nothing stops US boats on
the ground in Kashmir but as you know
there are no US troops on the ground as
far as we know uh on Pakistan territory
as as of as of now. Um in the past you
had US military presence in Pakistan at
at a time during those 20 years when the
Afghanistan was under US occupation. At
that time the US had you know military
presence in Pakistan but it also at that
time the US at the time sought to have a
decent working relationship with India
right it wasn't the kind of relationship
we have today and that's why they did
not send US troops in KJK or whatever
Pakistan occup
as far as I know did they have transit
routes through Pakistan occupied Kashmir
it's possible but as as far as we know
there was no report of US troops on the
ground during those 20 is now things are
different. The US has a containment
policy towards India. US the US has a
policy of bullying India essentially,
right? Uh so things may change now. So
right now the US doesn't have a military
presence that we know of in Pakistan.
But if there's an Iran regime change
then you will have US troops on the
ground in Iran. You will have that
and because of that you may also have
spill over into Pakistan. So right now
the US doesn't have boats on the ground
in Pakistan but they are overflying
Pakistan you know the Balojasthan region
just on the border of Iran they're
flying over the American aircraft
military aircraft are flying over that
region so eventually if Iran is regime
changed or invaded then you will have a
US presence in Pakistan because maybe
one part of the invasion may come
through Pakistan so once you have US
troops on the ground in Pakistani
territory it won't be long before they
may perhaps come into Pakistan on
occupied Kashmir because now the
relationship with India is different.
The US seeks to contain India. So that
is the logic. There is no hard and fast
you know uh let's say uh causal
relationship between this or that but
yeah Bascar Bandit says December 2025
leftant general Sarvanov was killed in a
car explosion operations head and 3 days
ago lift general general Alex Seyv
deputy Russian military intelligence was
shot. He's now in the ICU. This happens
when P stocks are going. That's one. Uh,
what fault line? No.
Okay. So, this is the Yeah, this is a
question. There's no continuation of the
questions. Okay. So, this happens when
peace talks are going on.
Um, this will happen while peace talks
are going on because talks are
happening, talks for peace supposedly,
but the war is also going on. The war is
continuing. So while two nations are in
a state of war, even if they are having
peace talks, there's going to be
hostilities, right? And the Ukrainians
who are obviously proxies of the west
will seek to, you know, take every
action possible
uh on the military front that could give
them some leverage in diplomatic talks
in in negotiations. So if you weaken
Russia in some way, it gives you
leverage on the diplomatic uh front. So
yeah. So, Lieutenant Lieutenant General
Alex allev
there was an assassination attempt
against him. He was shot twice point
blank in the back and the assassin
wasn't able to finish the job because
the lieutenant general fought back. He's
a guy in his 50s if I'm not mistaken,
but he fought back and he despite being
shot twice in the back, he still fought
back. He was shot a third time, but he
still kept fighting and that's why he's
alive. He's in the ICU, but he may, I
suppose, survive. So yeah, that's the
situation. Bascar Bandit says, "What
fault lines in the US and their society
exist that Bat can allegedly make use of
or exploit just as they do or have done
almost everywhere in the world."
Look, what I would recommend is let's
not try of let's not talk about
exploiting fault lines in the US. We
India is is no match for the US. India
should not even think about this right
now or at any given point in time
anytime in the future in the foreseeable
future India should play defense.
Okay, you try to mess around with the US
they're going to mess you up very badly.
So what I would say India should play
defense. Whatever fault lines exist
within India we need to fix those
instead of making them worse. That's
what I would suggest. Let's not try and
take on the US. I do not recommend that
at all. It's too powerful. they have
their issues. Uh we hope they solve
their issues and resolve those issues.
We don't want to go and tangle with them
and try and interfere in their internal
affairs and we will recommend to the US
don't interfere in our internal affairs.
That's the kind of relationship we want.
So that's all I will say about this
matter.
Pascar Bandit says we discussed that US
is trying to change global world order
entirely. A new one that will benefit
the US just as it did post the second
world war.
What changes can one expect that to see
that people are not expecting at all? So
you're going to see a complete collapse
of the WTO kind of the structure the the
World Trade Organization and everything
that was built around that that aspect
of international law that's gone. um
that's gone and all the the the uh
economic and uh other relationships that
the US has with various nations will be
on a one-toone basis. Uh with the EU it
may still be kind of what what it is but
in a different way. The US will be way
more forceful, way more assertive but
the question really you're asking is
what can we expect to see that people
are not expecting? Well, if people are
not expecting it, then we can't expect
to. So, what can we expect that most
people don't expect?
We can expect,
see, let me explain the game plan of the
US. The G the game plan is to isolate
every the game plan of the US right now
is to capture all supply chains, all
trade routes and all sources of
hydrocarbon energy
apart from Russia.
Okay. So that's why they did what they
did in Venezuela and that's why they may
even go ahead with whatever uh regime
change plans they may have visa v Iran
that will place a lot of pressure on
India and China. Now the US is insisting
in the I'm I'm sure there there'll be
questions about the trade deal the
interim trade thing whatever. So the US
insists that India should not buy
Russian oil and India seems to have kind
of agreed to it potentially.
So the US wants to control all sources
of energy which will make other nations
dependent on US demands or US
requirements for what they do.
And if the US takes Iran also then that
places China in a very difficult
position where they have to depend
almost entirely on Russia for energy.
Okay. and then the US can take Russia to
the negotiating table and give them a
great deal on Ukraine
with the condition that you stop
supplying China with energy that that
can be a disaster for China if Russia is
tempted to do that. So that's the kind
of stuff that's happening. Apart from
that, the US is wants to control all
critical minerals, all supply chains,
all trade routes, uh AI, all the high
technology, all of that the US wants to
control. It wants to create a uniolar
world. Actually, that's what we are
seeing.
Baser Bandit says, what's the
geopolitical angle or my analysis of the
situation in Nigeria? People getting
massacred by radical groups for
resisting conversions and so on. Okay,
Nigeria. Nigeria is this nation that's
kind of divided into two religious uh
demographics.
The northern part of Nigeria you have uh
people who are Islamic uh people who are
Muslim. The southern part of Nigeria you
have people who are Christians. So both
are foreign religions to Africa and
people have been converted by either uh
Arabic invaders or by uh European
invaders. Right? So the nation is kind
of split into two religious
demographics. I think the number of
Muslims may be slightly more than the
number of Christians. maybe 6040 or
something. Let's let's let's uh find out
religious demographics of Nigeria. I
would expect very few people practice
indigenous religion or culture in
Nigeria. Nigeria rel uh Nigeria
religious
demographics. Let's see.
Uh 43 to 48% Christian and 50 to 56%
Muslim. Okay. And you have this terrible
religious violence that's happening in
Nigeria. You have this terrorist group
called Boo Haram that kills Christians.
I don't think the Christians are
massacring Muslims as far as I know. But
the Boo Haram terrorist group is
abducting Christian girls and massacring
Christians and all that. Essentially,
it's Nigerians killing Nigerians driven
by external religious uh forces. That's
what's happening now. That's obviously a
terrible humanitarian situation. And you
have all this happening all the time,
right? Every few days some new horror
story comes out of Nigeria of Baku Haram
killing various civilians essentially
the question Baskar is asking what's the
geopolitical angle in this okay so
geopolitical if you want to look at it
what is Nigeria known for okay Nigeria
Nigeria
uh natural
resources let's see what natural
resources does Nigeria have uh rich
except Exceptionally rich in natural
natural resources. Petroleum and natural
gas as the cornerstone of the economy.
Nigeria is a top producer of crude oil
and natural gas in Africa.
Over 40 different kind types of minerals
limestone, barite, cowin, gypsum,
marble, tin, columbite, iron, ore, lead,
zinc, gold, copper, coal, bitamin,
uranium.
As you can see, uh agricultural
resources are significant. Cocoa,
rubber, palm oil, various food crops,
fertile land. Um Nigeria
oil reserves let's see oil reserves
uh it's about 10th or 11th globally in
terms of uh oil reserves. produces high
quality light sweet sweet crude the the
best kind of crude you want light sweet
crude is the ideal crude oil right so
that's what it produces so now you have
this nation that is rich in resources
exceptionally rich in resources one of
the top 10 suppliers you know nation one
of the top 10 nations essentially 10th
or 11th in terms of oil reserves if you
are an external geopolitical actor and
you want to control the world's oil
reserves. You want to control Nigeria.
Okay, this is all hypothetically. Okay,
I'm not naming any specific nation. So,
let's say if you are a global
superpower,
hypothetical global superpower and you
want to control Nigeria. How do you
control that? How do you control the
government, you do that by destabilizing
the country what's a great way of
destabilizing destabilizing a country?
Religious strife. Constant neverending
religious strife.
That could be a viable geopolitical
angle. Completely hypothetical of
course.
Okay.
Baser Bandit says, "If Dharma compelled
the majority population of Barat to not
get brainwashed or coerced to change
their religion in 1,000 years of
invasions, etc., why how were we so
easily divided by this fiction of cast
system by the British?" That's a great
question.
So the British introduced this cast
system. They made it mandatory in all
forms and all government documents and
all. I think about when was it 1891 1900
around that time let's say 120 years ago
at that time people did not really
understand this thing okay people knew
there are four verers hypothetically but
people all they what really mattered to
people was their jati right what jati
jati is all about economic occupation
that was what really mattered to people
or jati jati right that that's the kind
of question people ask they don't say
Right? So jati was what mattered but the
British imposed superimposed these four
casts and made it like cast in stone. So
for the longest time nobody knew about
Verna people still cared about jati even
after 1947 it was all jati it's only
after the mundal commission and VP Singh
bringing resol what reservations that's
when everybody became cast conscious
at least you know the youngsters and of
course in various parts of India some
parts of India you had cast politics and
so on but that was based on jatis it was
based on jatis not vera but now
everything has become vera based after
the mundal commission and the the
reservations based on cast. So the
question is how did Indians who resisted
all the you know u resisted a thousand
years of invasions and occupation
suddenly get over time brainwashed by
this uh cast system fiction. How did
this happen? It's
and dharma is dharma our dharma our our
our culture is what uh prevented us from
getting brainwashed and it kept us
resisting the foreigners. So what
happened now? What happened now is that
until the British as long as the British
were in India, India was still a dharmic
nation.
Okay. Um
the British had their molan education
system and all that but most people
still uh most people in India were
uneducated as in the modern sense of the
word until 1947
because very few people actually went
through the British education system
only those who learned English could do
that. Most people did not have access to
that. So most pe most Indians remained
kind of illiterate from today's
perspective
but they would be taught
reading writing etc in temples etc or
maybe by their elders and they were very
rooted in our culture and civilization.
But once education became mandatory and
education became widespread over the
1950s 60s7s 80s and jobs depended on
education and how well you spoke English
that's when we started becoming
dassinated because the education system
of India the current one it's a coronial
system it's entirely adheric it's not
non-darmic it is adharmic
so after 1947 India became a secular
nation a non-dharmic nation and that's
where everything starts going wrong and
every
generation
see generation after generation the
the dassination is increasing in India
because look at the education system
does it teach you anything about your
culture about your history about your
civilization everything is distorted and
it doesn't teach you your culture at all
because teaching culture would be not
secular because our culture is what it's
dharma right you can't teach that in a
secular nation
So kids spend like 15 year I don't know
how many years they spend in the
education system maybe 20 years in those
20 years they're brainwashed all the
dharma is brainwashed out out of them
and that's why they'll believe anything
they're taught that's the situation for
a thousand years despite being under
foreign occupation we still were dharmic
during the Turkish occupation we were
still dharmic
after the British came and imposed the
Macauian system That's when the
dharmicness was slowly slowly eroded
away that even until the 1940s we were
still very dharmic. It's only after we
got our supposed independence that
generation after generation you had
progressive more and more dassination.
And today's generations are super
dassinated. They think of Hinduism as
something exotic.
Something exotic. Yeah. They they see
our culture from the perspective of
foreigners. That's what's happened and
that's why everything has gone wrong and
this is just getting worse every
generation. Um the education system as
I've said many times is trash. It is
rotten. Your new education policy is
going to do nothing to solve the issues.
Uh Raki Ganwani says why are so many
westerners
converted claiming that Hinduism rigid
it's is created by arans and not
Indians. I don't know why it's making me
less devout to my religion. So because
some westerners are claiming this, it
makes you less devout. That's uh
unfortunate,
right? See the the situation in in India
is that because of our education system,
we look up to to foreigners. We think
that foreigners are superior to us. We
think that everything good in the world
was created by foreigners, by white
people, by white-kinned people. And we
brown-skinned Indians are losers. Our
culture is trash. It's rubbish. Our
culture is misogynistic, patriarchal,
backward, primitive, castist, every
every adjective you can think of, every
negative adjective you can think of, you
think of you think of your culture in
that way. And when you are taught these
things, you will automatically think
that if you are a white-skinned person
who speaks English, you are superior,
right? And
the one of the biggest issues is the
English language because we Indians
speak English with an Indian accent,
right? But when you have a white person
who speaks English with a foreign
accent, that automatic automatically
sounds superior to Indians because
Indians can't pronounce certain English
words the way the British or the
Americans do, right? So we think that
that makes them automatically superior
to us.
And then when they make these ridiculous
claims that Hinduism and the rigid and
everything came
through white-skinned invaders, the
Arian invaders
and that these Arian invaders came from
Europe or somewhere or central Asia,
white-skinned people, they subjugated
the native Dravidians as per this claim
and imposed this evil Hinduism, evil
cast system, evil in Sanskrit language.
So that makes it sound like Hinduism,
Sanskrit, everything is evil. And when
white people make the claim, Indians
automatically believe that's true. And
then they feel that our religion is bad.
No cho, let's convert to their religion.
That's the objective.
This Arian invasion theory which then
was modified into an Arian migration
theory.
Yeah. What's the objective of the Arian
invasion and migration theory? Let me
tell you. Okay. First of all, I will
recommend if you are if okay Arian
invasion myth chavda India facts let's
go to India facts okay this is an
article I wrote um one second what is
the let me see the AI AI thing
what does the AI summary say it is work
published in India fact characterizes
the AIT as 19th century colonial myth
designed to facilitate British imperial
rule by creating artificial racial and
social divisions in India there we have
That's what I have indeed said. Um,
right. Okay. So that's what it says
about that's a summary it gives about
what I have written in this in this
article and this article was published
in 2017. That's 9 years ago now. Wow.
Prime has flown. So uh contextualizing
this thing
uh
let's see some let's see
uh okay so
let give me a second let me find the
okay here we have it
so
the question of the origin of the
indoorance concerns the very idea of
India it pits two diametrically opposing
narratives against one
The mainstream Marian invasion theory or
migration theory narrative which
portrays Hindu culture as hegemonic,
racist, intolerant, rapeious and ine
inegalitarian
imposes an Indian version of white guilt
on persons of supposed Indo-arian
ancestry and engenders deep resentment
and a desire to write historical wrongs
amongst people of so-called Dravidian
and so-called Dalith ancestry which
manifests itself in various forms such
as separatism and rejection of Hinduism
and Indian culture among others. So this
is a power this this makes the this
theory a powerful political tool which
dovetailes perfectly with the leftist
secular and liberal political narrative
as well as the agendas of various
nationalists drained nationalists Dalit
supremacists missionaries separatists
and other breaking India forces um it's
been used to neatly divide India into
dichomous categories such as north and
south Indians arians and dravidians
fairkinned and dark-kinned so-called
high high cast and so-called low casts
the privileged and the oppressed this
has strengthened leftist narrative and
so on. So read this thing and understand
what the actual objective of this theory
is. Okay. So my point is please don't
get fooled by these things
and it's it's sad to see that it's
making you less devout to your religion.
Your religion it's not the religion of
pedophiles and child eaters and
cannibals.
That is white culture. You are seeing
that very openly now.
That's not our culture. Our culture is
superior. We've never had pedophiles.
We've never had Epstein. We've never had
child eaters.
We don't have that. That is their
culture. It's it's been in their culture
for like 3,000 years. That's their
culture. Your religion is a good
religion, but you are being taught
taught the opposite of that. That's the
problem.
Pascar Bandit says, "What is the
signaling here? Is this not escalation?
Oh, that's the continuation of the the
the other story, the assassination
attempt. Okay. What's the signality
here? Is this not escalation? Attacking
such high ranks and that too inside
Russia when they are in discussion in
Abu Dhabi, that's all. Like I said, it's
it's all the objective is to gain some
more leverage for for your negotiations.
When you are at war and you're also
negotiating simultaneously, you want
leverage. And if you are doing better
than the adversary on the battlefield,
you have more leverage on the on the
negotiating table. So yeah, it makes
sense to do these things when you're,
you know, engaged in diplomatic
negotiations at the same time that
you're at war. So it's is it an
escalation? Sure, it's an escalation.
Yeah, they want to use that as as
negotiating as leverage in negotiations.
Harish Sharma says, "Will exposure to
gamma rays turn me into the Hulk?"
Exposure to gamma rays will give you
cancer. It won't turn you into into the
Hulk. And if you get if you are exposed
to very large quantities of gamma rays,
it'll give you radiation sickness and
it'll kill you in a matter of hours or
days. So stay away from gamma rays.
Okay. My honest advice, stay away from
gamma rays. Minimalist Maverick says,
"Why did Modi sing and dance for US
president in Israel? Do you trust
Israel?" Look, when you say somebody
sang and danced, it means that you went
out and put your best foot forward. It
doesn't mean somebody actually literally
sang and danced.
Okay? It's it's a euphemism. Mr. Modi
went to Israel. Which year was it Modi's
first trip to Israel? Let's find out.
Uh, which year did Modi visit Israel
for the the first time as PM?
Which year did Modi visit Israel for the
first time in the Okay, it was 2017. So,
Mr. Modi visited Israel for the first
time, the first ever Indian prime
minister to visit Israel and he went out
went there with the objective of
significantly strengthening India Israel
relations
and he
he he did so many public meetings and so
many uh meetings with various Israeli uh
you know high ranking people and so many
things. So that is what someone was
calling singing and dancing. It doesn't
mean literally singing and dancing.
Okay. Okay. Honey Sharma says, "Was
yesterday's match match part of the
trade deal?" Well, yesterday's match
turned out to be in India's favor
despite the initial significant hiccups.
So, I'm not sure it was part of the
trade deal. The trade deal is supposed
to favor the stronger side, isn't it?
See, in any deal between two sides, the
stronger side, the more powerful side
always gets the better end of the deal.
So if it if the match is part of the
trade deal then India should have lost
to the US yesterday but did not work out
that way. So clearly not part of the
deal. Ritik power says is it possible
for a person with AI to take over power
for example Elon or Sam Alman using
their AI to take control of the US
government and military and rule the
world.
Well it's possible if you give AI
agency. What's agency?
What's agency?
Well, I'm not sure how to exactly define
agency. The ability to get things done.
That's agency. Let's see what Google
defines as agency. Okay. Uh define
agency.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. Um
agency to have agency. Yeah. What does
it mean to have agency? Possessing the
power, capacity, and autonomy to make
your own free choices, take independent
actions, and intentionally influence
your life circumstances. If you give AI
this sort of agency, if you allow AI to
possess the power, capacity and autonomy
to make its own free choices to take
independent actions and to do all that,
then
you can take control of the world if AI
continues obeying you. Otherwise, it
will it'll run riot. So, it's possible
for a person with AI to take over power
if the AI is given agency. if it can
make real world choices, real world
decisions and actually change real world
things. So AI right now is just
software. It can produce text right the
large language models are chat bots.
They produce text. They can generate
images now even video. But it's all on
your screens, right? If I tell AI, give
me a different kind of microphone, you
know, phone. See that's the microphone
beneath. I have this one. I want
something with a different shape. Can AI
do it for me? AI can't, right? AI can't
do that. If I ask AI to redesign my
house, like the real house, can it do
it? It can't. But if I give AI the tools
to do that, that's when AI can start
making real world changes. And if you
give AI access to weapons and access to
various things, that's when you can
start taking over power. So
theoretically, it's possible, but in
practice, very difficult as of today at
least.
Sagnik Acharia says, "Please explain how
was the US able to subjugate Nazi
Germany ideology once and for all post
second world war after defeating the ger
Nazi Germany. How did that ideology
never rose again?
Never rose ever again. And how come
Germans were okay with white collar US
slavery?" Um, okay. How come Germany was
okay? How come German people were okay
with US occupation?
First of all, they had no choice.
Germany was flattened essentially by the
time the Second World War ended. Germany
was brutalized.
Germany was a nation filled with rubble.
Okay. The Germans that were alive, they
were just thanking thankful to God that
they were still alive. And many of them
who were who had survived they went
through well what can I say?
Yeah.
So the point is the Germans were in no
position to not be okay. They were in no
position to say we don't we are not okay
with this.
That's what happens when you were
defeated. You have to accept whatever
deal is given to you. Okay. And the ger
the Americans after the the the dust
cleared and everything after Germany was
fully under the US control they gave
Germany a nice the people of Germany a
nice deal Germany as a nation was
enslaved it still is it's under
permanent US military occupation un in
case you're not aware even today it's
under US military occupation but Germany
was given a decent deal at least the
people of Germany that we will rebuild
your nation we we will give you a
constitution that will apparently be
written by your
and you'll be allowed to have uh you
know a functioning government and all
that and West Germany will will be under
US occupation.
East Germany will be under Soviet
occupation or aligned with USSR and so
on. So because of military might the
Americans were able to do whatever they
want in West Germany, West Germany, not
East Germany. Um
and what about Nazi ideology? The
Americans did not have any actual issue
with Nazi ideology. They had an issue
with Germany rising again. Whether it's
Nazi ideology or leftist ideology or
some other ideology doesn't matter. They
did not want Germany rising. They could
they saw what Germany was capable of.
They saw what the people of Germany were
capable of. Right? So what the Americans
did was they took the best scientists
and engineers out of Germany, shipped
them off to the US, all the best rocket
engineers and technicians and everybody.
and the rest of these engineers and
scientists were taken by the Russians.
All the good stuff was go, all the good
people were gone. And um
and Nazi ideology, the US don't care. I
mean, the the former head of NATO was
Hitler's former chief of staff, right?
Nazi head of NATO. Let's see this.
Adolf Hiser, right? Adolf Heisinger.
Adolf Buo Hinrich Ernst Heisinger was a
German military officer. Nazi German
Nazi military officer, former top vbach
German general in Nazi Germany. He then
served as the chairman of the NATO
military committee from 1961 to 1964.
Despite his role in Nazi military
leadership, Hoinger was appointed to
highranking NATO positions during the
Cold War, sparking protests regarding
his background. So, it's not like the US
cared about Nazi ideology, whatever.
They just did not want Germany to ever
rise again, right? And has Nazi ideology
disappeared entirely? Not quite. It
hasn't. There are still people who who
can be considered to be neo-Nazis or
whatever, right? Obviously, that's
terrible, but whatever. It's still there
kind of. Okay. Um, Yashwaran Yashard
Dan Seal says, "Big fan." Thank you so
much, sir. Thank you. Uh, in today's
geopolitical climate, does it make
strategic sense for Indians in Germany
or Europe to take a German passport? How
do you view Indians renouncing Indian
citizenship?
How do I view Indians renouncing Indian
I think it's a personal choice.
I don't view them badly. I don't view
such people badly.
When you're when you have a system in
India that gives everybody a raw deal, a
terrible deal, people will look out for
their own interests eventually. Let's
say you are a talented young person who
wants to pursue AI or robotics in India,
okay, and you get good marks in your GE
or whatever exam, but then you don't get
the seat because of reservations, you
will feel terrible about that. And let's
say even if you got the seat,
you got a seat, maybe you got 99% of
marks and maybe uh whatever you know. So
let's say you got a seat but then after
once you get into the IIT you find that
your whichever IIIT it is has a terrible
lab it has milliondoll washrooms and
conference rooms but the but the lab
equipment is 20 years behind today's
cutting edge standards maybe 30 years
behind today's cutting edge standards
and you can't do any research any
meaningful research there how will you
feel and even if you get the degree by
going through all this despite the
terrible professors and all the issues.
Let's say you get a degree and then you
want to have a job in AI, robotics or
whatever and there's no jobs available.
I mean, you're going to feel terrible,
right? So, you're going to want to get
the hell out of the country and then you
go maybe to the US or wherever and you
find such a different climate. They
welcome you. They like talent, they they
reward talent. You're going to take up a
citizenship there. What's wrong with
that?
I would like India to retain talent. But
the system in India is such that it it
it ensures there is brain drain.
So India doesn't hate Indians. The
system hates talent. It hates merit. The
system is rigged. The system is trash.
It's rotten. So obviously people will
leave India.
Yeah. And once they find that the
climate this the thing over there is so
much better
uh talent is rewarded merit is rewarded
they'll feel like taking citizenship and
I don't blame them for that so I don't
view them I I don't view them negatively
I think it's it's a personal choice and
it's very understandable
right and a lot of these people end up
end up hating India they're very bitter
about India they should my message to
them is that India doesn't hate you.
It's the system that hates talent, the
system that has been put in place
well postindependence
and the system is getting worse actually
you have more issues now in UGC and
whatnot and it's getting worse so so
people will leave right what do you
expect uh now the question is in today's
geopolitical climate does it make
strategic sense for Indians to in
Germany or Europe to take a German
passport
it may still make sense
uh long-term I think Europe uh will
diminish as a geopolitical power. Europe
isn't a geopolitical power as such. Uh
NATO is but NATO is controlled by the
US. I think Europe is in slow decline
right now. But even in 20 years, I think
living standards in Europeans may still
be higher than those in India possibly.
So I don't think it makes sense for
Indians to if they desire a passport in
in the EU region, Shenhen region to not
go for it. At the end of the day, it's
your decision but u it still is not
it still makes sense possibly if you if
you have decided you'll take a foreign
passport and you have the option of a
German or EU passport somewhere. I think
it it it won't really hurt you or harm
harm your interests in the next 20
years.
Okay. Honey Sharma says, "Is Epstein
files just the the tip of the iceberg?"
I believe there are more heinous things
which the general public doesn't know
about. What are my thoughts? My
thoughts. Are the Epstein files just the
tip of the iceberg? Yes. My thoughts.
What I
Yeah. I I think that the Epstein files
are just the tip of the iceberg. The
Epstein files have exposed a lot of
these older people, right? All these old
guys who have been entrenched in power
in the corridors of power for decades,
they're all exposed. They're all Maybe
they won't be prosecuted, but they're
all exposed. Nobody will trust them
again. So why is this being done? Why
are they all being exposed? Because
maybe the system,
the deep state wants to sideline them
now. And maybe there's a whole new core
group of people who will now be the
people who will who will take over
power. Maybe it's the younger lot that
are being protected now. And maybe
they're also involved in God knows what
kind of things. Uh are there more
heinous things that the public doesn't
know about? Oh, most likely yes. I don't
know for sure, but most likely yes.
Knowing their culture, most likely, yes.
Knowing Western culture,
most likely there are far more heinous
things that have been hidden away and
the public doesn't know about.
Struggler says, "Thoughts of the 2008
nuclear deal?" No thoughts about it.
There was like what, 18 years ago. I'm
not sure what really has come out of it.
Um, did India purchase any US military I
mean US nuclear reactors? Did any
cooperation happen? I'm not really sure.
So I don't think about it.
Honey Sharma says, "What happened to
West India's cricket? They won the 2016
T20 World Cup." Oh yeah. What was the
name? Marlon Samuels got the Yeah.
against Sri Lanka, I think. So they won
the 2016 T20 World Cup and now they
struggle to be in the top 10. What
caused this downfall? Was it their
cricket board?
The West Indies cricket team was the
greatest team in the world from the late
from the mid 1970s, maybe late late
1970s all the way to maybe the early
90s. They were the greatest sports team
in the world. Not just cricket team,
greatest sports team in the world. They
they defeated everybody. They
steamrolled everyone. Then what
happened? Then you had the great
retiring. Vivven Richards retired.
Malcolm Marshall retired. Patrick
Patterson faded away. Uh Ambrose and
Walt retired. the great fast bowlers all
retired and the great batsman Grenidge
Haynes Richards
all those guys retired and then you had
people like Brian Lara take over. Brian
Lara was a tremendous batsman, one of
the two great batsman, one of the two
greats, right? The top two of the '90s,
Tendulkar and Lara. But then after
Richards retired and other captains took
over, you had a visible decline in
standards,
they sacked their performance coach, uh
their fitness coach, and fitness
standards started declining. They had
this fitness coach during Vivian
Richard's time who was an Australian I I
believe and he was he was sacked and
then things just started declining
standards started declining. It all
started with Brian Lara be becoming
captain that's how I see it. So why why
was there a decline? Why why did West
Indies cricket undergo this downfall and
it says it's just going downwards
because of a decline in standards. Once
standards start start declining and the
results no longer come in, young kids no
longer want to play the game. They want
to play something else. So that's why
you don't have u talented people coming
into and playing cricket anymore. So
look at the West Indies fast bowling uh
cupboard today. You have Shamar Joseph
who is good but who else do we have? I
can't think of any other great bowler
today. Shamar Joseph is good. I'm not
sure if he's great yet. Uh you had uh
Roach Kamar Roach who bowls in the 120s.
Now my grandma can bowl faster. Not his
fault.
He's old. He's he's older now. Uh but so
overall it's a declining standards that
has caused the downfall of West Indies
cricket. The greatest team of all time
possibly
it once was and now look at where they
are. They play at the same level as
perhaps Bangladesh and Afghanistan.
Sad
struggler 856 says Gilain Gileain
Maxwell's dad was Robert Maxwell MI6 KGB
and Mossad agent MI6 KGB Mossad also CIA
perhaps let's throw in I don't know look
I don't know whether he was an agent of
all three of these agencies but he seems
to have had some kind of close ties with
uh some intelligence agencies I don't
know which country he had closed ties
with Teresa
so-called Mother Teresa apparently this
seems deeper than we thought. Oh, it's
way deeper than anything you think. So,
so Robert Maxwell, right? He clearly had
some intelligence connections. I don't
know which intelligence agencies can't
be KGB, MI6, and Mossad at the same
time. That's what we like. He would be
the greatest of all spies in human
history then if that's the case. But
triple agent, maybe quadruple, I don't
know what. No. So, probably not the KGB.
Uh, Mossad 6. I'm not sure could be CIA
also could be who knows we don't know
but he seems to have had in intelligence
connections he also controlled the
peraman press which I am aware of
because it published a lot of physics
books you know hardcore physics books
graduate and post-graduate level physics
books when I say graduate I'm talking
about the master's degree level okay not
the Indian graduate thing in India
postgraduate is master's degree in
outside of India graduate level means
master's degree level and higher. So, u
Peramin Press published a lot of physics
textbooks and I'm sure other scientific
textbooks and uh Robert Maxwell also
yeah he had yeah all of this. So uh you
could say Robert Maxwell kind of ruined
uh physics publishing publishing
possibly and eventually u yeah he
apparently died I don't know at sea in
some way you can look up so he he also
had ties with this with this Teresa
character. Yeah. So yeah deeper than you
thought. Oh things go very deep and we
don't know even 1% of what what's going
on. So what we see is just the tip of
the iceberg that we are allowed to see.
What happens deep down we have no idea.
Pratarana good to see you sir. Rising
poverty and declining living standards.
US have put all the money in AI and
going all out on automation. This looks
like a disaster in the making. It may be
possibly eventually a disaster for the
common people. But for the people who
matter in the US, the people with the
money and the power, well it's not a
disaster. It's going to be fantastic for
them. They're going to control even more
power. They're going to have even more
money, right?
Um
if things go the way we ex we assume
they will. So yeah, see
history teaches us that the most
powerful empires are the ones with the
best technology.
So,
so the US obviously understands this and
they want to ensure that they are at the
forefront of every technological race in
the world. Right now the major
technological race is semiconductors
which is chips. It is uh AI obviously
because that's connected with
semiconductors and also robotics which
is connected to AI because AI and
robotics will change the world
and AI ensures that you know your
military is your decisions
are better they are faster
than those of your adversary. Your
strategies are better and faster than
those of your adversary. So if you uh uh
go to war with someone the nation with
the better AI wins. Okay. Strategic
strategic choices are better. And of
course if you have AI and robotics
enabled together. So the point is it's
all about power.
Yeah you have declining living
standards. Who cares? That's the common
people. Common people don't matter. If
you see the Epstein fires they are
trying to figure out ways of eliminating
a poor people because they're a burden
on the planet apparently. I mean that
sort of discussions have come out in the
Epstein fires. So poor people don't
matter right. uh rising poverty,
declining living standards, that doesn't
matter to the elite.
So it will be a disaster for uh the poor
people, the common people, the non
billionaire class, but for the
billionaire class and the trillionaire
class, doesn't matter. They'll enjoy.
Pratadana says Tajakistan, Afghanistan
should be called South Asia. I would
call them part of the subcontinent. I I
don't I'm not a big fan of the word of
the term South Asia. So uh let's quickly
take a look at the map and understand
what we're talking about.
So uh we have the Indian subcontinent
which includes I mean if you if you look
at it as a as a geopolitical term it
includes India, Sri Lanka, the Maldives
um including the Chigos archipelago, the
Lakship islands and the andabar islands
and Bangladesh, Bhutan uh Nepal,
Pakistan and Afghanistan. That's the
typical definition of the Indian
subcontinent.
Uh if you look at it as as a cultural
zone, you could also include Iran,
Persia in it because historically Persia
was very similar to uh India culturally
and then you also have to include
Tajakistan. So when Shri Chingis Khan u
entered India in the pursuit of the of
the coward Jalaludin uh
the uh border between India and central
Asia was somewhere in uh Tajakistan or
Turkmanistan somewhere here. Yeah, the
iron gates of sojana.
So, so let's look that up. The iron
gates of sdana that was the border
between India and central Asia. Once
that was crossed, Chingistan was in
India.
Iron gate of soana.
So, okay, it's in Usbakistan. Uh, do we
have a map? Can we find it on Z map?
Iron gate of Sukdana.
Oh, come on.
Let's take a look at it on satellite
imagery. Now, you won't find much over
here. Of course, today there won't be
real landmarks. But if you zoom out and
see where where it's geographically
located.
Okay. So, it is
um in present day. So, so that used to
be the border between central Asia and
the Indian subcontinent. Once you cross
the iron gates, you were into Indian
territory.
That's how it was. and they won't teach
you this in your history textbooks. I
wonder why right one won this why. So uh
that's how it was. So I would agree with
you that you know you should definitely
include Afghanistan and even Tajakistan
in uh what we what we call uh the Indian
subcontinent. I am not a fan of the term
South Asia but right
uh Rajes Daswani thank you very much sir
indeed. Thank you.
Tanesh Pande says, "I feel sad reading
about Maratalite infantry. They fought
for Britain in both the second world,
both the world wars and defeated the the
Japanese, the Ottomans, and they fought
in Africa and won in Africa as well.
Such a strong martial history. And yet
Maratas lost our nation to them, to the
British." Yeah. Well, India's history
the past 10,000 years is tragic.
It's tragic. That's why a lot of Indians
have this defeatist mentality, this
inferiority complex because the past
1,000 years of our history has been a
millennium of humiliation, a millennium
of occupation and genocide. Right? The
Marata Empire had turned the tide.
But in the what 1810s and 1820s, by 1820
the British were able to defeat the
Maratas. And that was tragic. Sad. The
maratas had liberated India the
subcontinent from the Turks. They had
re-established what you know Hindavis
but because of infighting and internal
issues the British were able to overcome
the maratas and that's tragic tragic
absolutely tragic.
Anoj art says if world war II happens
will it be due to religion or resources?
It will be because of great power
competition over resources and over
supremacy over the world. If it happens,
it will probably be because of some
stupid accident somewhere. Somebody
launching a missile they were not
supposed to launch or something, right?
It won't be because of religion. No, it
won't be because of religion. Wars are
not for I mean, yeah, you've had wars
fought over religion, but uh in today's
context, it won't be religion. It will
be
uh over the competition for resources or
competition for supremacy, global
supremacy.
Brown Leprechaun says, "Why is it so
difficult for the common American people
to surrender their guns?"
Because they should not surrender their
guns. Why should they?
It if you have weapons for self-defense,
it gives you liberty. Indians don't
understand this because after 1857, we
were made to surrender our weapons. Look
at old paintings of India done by the
British. You have Indians carrying
weapons whether it is swords, whether it
is spears or whatever. Indians, all
Indians carried weapons.
Then we were made to surrender our
weapons. Uh when were Indians made to
surren Let's let's this is an
interesting question actually. When were
Indians
made to surrender their weapons by the
British?
Let's see. There was some law or
something passed. Indian Arms Act of
1878.
Okay. Indians were made were formally
made to surrender their weapons and
required to obtain licenses for arms
under the Indian Arms Act of 1878. This
was passed during the vice royalty of
Lord Littton to restrict Indian access
to firearms and prevent future armed
uprisings
especially following the revolt of 1857
the war of independence 1857.
Uh so this ma this act made it a
criminal offense for Indians to carry or
possess possess arms of any description
without a license. It was highly
discriminatory as it did not apply to
British citizens, Europeans or Eurasians
who were allowed to carry arms freely.
Um severely restricted Indians from
owning weapons which Gandhi later
described as the blackest of all the
abuses of the British administration.
Very funny. I mean that's a uh
that is indeed ironic.
Um so the British made Indians surrender
their weapons and after 1947 we have
still been made to you know we are not
allowed to have weapons. Indians freely
had weapons before this hideous arms act
came to power came into force and today
Indians are born not born what is born
now what sort of grammar is Indians are
born today Indians are born
surrendered
helpless
right and that's why Indians think what
is so bad about not having weapons
it was our birthright to to own and
carry weapons in public
for thousands of years. What we are
living through is unnatural.
Okay.
And and after 47
the free the government of free India
has kept Indians unarmed.
Is it a good thing? Is it a bad thing?
Well, today you will you will see it as
a good thing because this is the world
you born into. This is the India you
born into. But the Americans, they have
weapons and they regarded as their
birthright to to to ensure that they
don't there is no tyranny that the
government doesn't become tyrannical
that there's a people's militia that can
uh resist any tyranny if there's tyranny
from the government or or whoever else
people should be able to defend
themselves.
So yeah,
Sam the Gamer says, "Are gods just our
ancestors?" Well,
that's a good question. The rigida says
in the nasa sutta that the gods were
born with the universe, right? Before
the universe was created, even the gods
did not exist. So, who created them? Who
created the universe? That's the
question, right? Um it's a pretty
agnostic and skeptical outlook that we
have in the nasi nasad. So if the gods
were created with the creation of the
universe and they came after the birth
of the universe, maybe they were the
original human beings perhaps or maybe
the great heroes. Maybe Lord Indra was
just a great warrior who did something
incredible you know in battle and that's
why he's revered as a god. We know that
Lord Krishna and Lord Ram were human
beings and they did such great things
that we regard them as avatars of
Vishnu. Right?
Only an avatar of Vishnu could do the
things that that someone like Shriram or
Sri Krishna could could do and Lord
Indra is is a rigidic god like before
the Ramayan and the Mahabharat. So maybe
the Rigida was referring to the memory
of a great warrior called Indra. So
maybe Indra is a is an ancestor for
ancestor of ours of the Arya people.
Yeah. So and definitely Shri Ram Shir
Krishna maybe their blood flows in our
veins you know a little bit of that. So
maybe many of our gods perhaps are our
ancestors. Yeah. But yes, in in what we
call Hinduism, Hindu dharma, there's one
god that cannot be our ancestor and
that's probably Lord Shiva, right? The
God who wasn't born and who doesn't die.
The God who probably came before the
universe. Maybe maybe he is the I think
Lord Shiva and the Trimmorti they are
the only truly supernatural entity in
our culture in our civilization right
thei brahma Vishnu and Shiva three
aspects of the same divinity that's the
only truly supernatural being the others
maybe are memories of ancestors memories
of great heroes
24 be has become a new member thank you
so much sir or ma'am welcome to the
membership of the channel it is Very
much appreciated.
General Subutai says the Marata has
prepared for 70 plus years to defeat the
Mughals maintaining a day one mindset
despite tactical shifts. What can we
learn from Chhatraatishwaji Maharaj
regarding civilizational threats from
us?
See today Indians are super complacent.
Super complacent. Somebody will solve
our problems.
You know most Indians are not even aware
of the threats that that India faces. We
may be in the last decades of Hinduism
of our of our culture. We could be in
the last few decades that our culture
survives.
You know
our culture our our religion whatever
you want to call it has been around for
definitely 10,000 years. And we could be
it could be on its last legs right now
and we are complacent and uh we are
increasingly dassinated. Nobody young
Indians don't even care anymore about
their culture.
Right? So that's happening in front of
our eyes. We are witnessing possibly the
end of our civilization right now in
front of our eyes in slow motion.
So what can we learn from Sudarat Shiva
Jaraj?
Well,
take up arms and fight back. I mean,
that's what he would do. I I cannot ask
you to take up arms because then that is
that is
not it is the opposite of a hinsa,
right? And obviously you don't want to
fight your own people or whatever. My
point is you have to be aware of what's
happening. Chhatra Maharaj was aware of
the threats that India faced or he was
aware of the uh civilizational threats
that we faced. Indians today aren't. So
that's one thing I would say. Develop
the awareness
of what the what are the forces that are
working against us. Not just externally
but internally as well.
And look the Maratas prepared for 70
plus years to defend the muggles. The
muggles. Have you heard of the
reconista?
Just an example. I'm not saying it
should happen in India or whatever.
Reconista.
the Spanish reconista. Okay. U which was
the Spaniards retaking Spain from the
from the Moors, the Arabs. It's see when
does it start?
7:22 AD. The Rekumista starts in 722 AD.
It ends with victory in 1492 AD.
That is 770 years it took for the
Spaniards to reclaim their their country
and their culture. It took them 770
years.
Sometimes you got to fight for centuries
to reclaim what is yours. Yeah. Okay.
Shatabish says Marco Rubio in age of
disclosure acknowledged ET presence.
Ignoring it's always US joke. Isn't it a
big deal coming from a sitting uh SOS,
Secretary of State of a Superpower?
Maybe he's lying. I don't know.
I mean, he has said something verbally.
Has he produced any evidence?
Maybe he's lying. His boss Trump lies
all the time. His boss Trump, Marco
Rubio's boss, Trump is a well-known
gaslighter.
Gaslighting involves a lot of lying.
So if your boss does that, maybe the
boss instructed you to make these
claims, so-called disclosure.
Yeah. So until and unless I see actual
hard evidence, I will not believe any of
this. That is the way I I I see things.
Just because somebody admitted or
claimed something doesn't make it true.
Maybe he's lying.
Sid the way says why did Buddhism
Zoroastrianism decline in Iran,
Afghanistan, India? Is it because they
were dependent on state support where
institutional Hinduism was too
decentralized? Cast system prevented
Islam Islamization.
See, let's not call it the cast system.
It was the vernati system. The vernati
system, not the cast system. The cast
system was introduced in India by the
British in the late 19th and early 20th
century. The cast system. We had the
vernadi system which is very different
from the cast system that has been
imposed on you today. So coming back to
the question of Buddhism, Zoroastrianism
etc. decline.
See,
Zoroastrianism,
the religion that Zaratustra brought in,
it was probably a religion that was
super imposed on the people of Iran top
down possibly because in just a few
decades, see, as far as we know, Kurush
was not zorastrian. Okay, look, Cyrus,
uh, Cyrus the great
religion. What was his religion?
Okay, he was a follower of early
zeroastrianism.
Religious tolerance. M. That's okay.
Marduk Fararduk, we don't care. Who came
before Cyrus? Let's just see who was
before Cyrus. What? Who was his
predecessor? Kambuja.
Camb
religion. What was his religion?
What was his religion? Early form of
Zora. Everything is early form of Okay.
Uh, which
was the religion
of Persia before Zurastas? Now look at
the answer that this gives you. Okay.
Before Zorastianism,
ancient Persians practiced an Indo
Iranian religion, a polytheistic faith.
What was it called? They won't answer
that. sharing roots with Vic traditions.
It was Hinduism.
So, Hinduism is a super decentralized
religion. Let's say if you want if you
want to call it religion, super
decentralized. It has absorbed so many
practices and brought them together.
animist practices, nature worshiing
practices, worshipping of forests and
nature spirits, ancestor worship, all
kinds of local deities and divinities,
they've all been subsumed into one
single civilizational structure. It's
incredibly decentralized.
And in the Hinduism doesn't have a top-
down pyramidal structure, a pope and
then cardinals and bishops and whatnot.
Nothing like that. I'm not sure how it
was with Zoroastrinism.
They have the the the dust, right? They
have the the the the priests who do the
fire worship and all. So it looks like
Zoroastronism was not decentralized.
Maybe the power was structure was
centralized and when the top people were
were killed off by the Arabs, it just
disintegrated just like that. And that's
why Persians converted so so fast in a
matter of like two three decades
entirely almost entirely to Islam. And
those persons who did not want to
convert, they were horribly persecuted
and a lot of them escaped and came to
India. Where else will they go? Right?
Uh Buddhism,
Buddhism once again was
why did Buddhism become so big in India
so quickly? Because of imperial
patronage from Ashoke.
It art it was it became this artificial
phenomenon in India. Buddhism it was one
of the small fringe
dharmic dharmic paths and Ashok said
okay I'm going to make it big and he in
just during his reign during the reign
of one emperor Buddhism become so big so
once again it was not decentralized it
was like a top- down thing you take out
the top everything is gone crumbles so
wherever you had Buddhism in central
Asia in Gandhar wherever else once the
Turks came in everyone converted just
like that who were the gories the gories
were originally Buddhists
they were Indians
and then the first goi converted to
Islam and then Gandhar just falls.
So wherever you had Zoroastrinism and
Buddhism you had a like super rapid
conversion to Islam. Wherever you had
Hinduism did not work at all. Hinduism
Hinduism was so deeply entrenched for
like 10,000 plus years that it was just
impossible to remove it. And the verati
system also contributed significantly
to people refusing
Because you know you can destroy the
temples, kill off the priests but in
your own jati you have your own
traditions that have not come from any
priests any any any temple or whatever
that these are your own traditions that
have gone that go back centuries maybe
millennia you won't get rid of that so
the vagati system prevented uh people
from you know it it made people resist
the efforts to convert Indians to
foreign religions right
Jew Warrior says, "Do you think there
will come a time when both the US and
China will ditch Pakistan? Under what
circumstances do you think that will
happen the US and China will ditch
Pakistan if India crumbles? If India
becomes a full vasal?
Even if India becomes a full vasal,
Pakistan will still be useful to keep
India still as a vasal on the back
foot."
Okay, let's take this hypothetical
example. Okay. In various uh South
American countries, you have this drug
cartels,
right? Medí, Kali, take the take the
example of Colombia.
In these South American countries, you
have drug cartels. In Mexico, you have
drug cartels. All these countries in
Central and South America, they are
American basals.
What is the use of these drug cartels?
to keep the nation destabilized
and keep the government permanently on
the back foot. So the drug cartel
counterbalances the government, the
government counterbalances the drug
cartel and you have this uneasy balance
and when you have a nation like that you
can it's so easy to control. You can
keep funding both sides if you need.
It's a totally hypothetical example. Of
course, when it comes to India, even if
the Americans are able to totally
vaselize India, they'll still still keep
Pakistan afloat just as an insurance
policy. So, when will there come a time
when the US and China will ditch
Pakistan? When India becomes way too
powerful for Pakistan to continue
existing when India becomes
significantly more powerful than what it
is today, let's say twice as powerful.
Uh in terms of GDP, let's let's say 10
10 trillion. that GDP is not enough. You
will need the right kind of leadership.
But when you are at that stage, when you
have that forceful,
nononsense, hard-nosed leadership and a
massive economy and military, Pakistan
automatically crumbles. Then the US and
China will have no option but to ditch
Pakistan. So when India becomes the most
powerful entity in the subcontinent,
Pakistan will automatically break up and
then the US and China will won't be able
to do a thing about that. But if India
is vasalized in the next 5 years which
is a significant possibility then they
will keep Pakistan afloat as an
insurance policy against India.
Sergeant Skylan says is Black Rockck
coming to India? I am not aware. I I
don't know. Black Rockck is a is is this
massive entity that invests in very big
companies and essentially
owns half the world. Is it in India? Is
it coming to India? I'm not sure. Not
sure. Madav Gupta says history question.
Namaskar. Okay. Namaskar. If Chingishan
would have crossed the river that day,
do you think we would have never been
colonized by the muggles or the Brits?
That's an interesting question. So at
that time uh it was the year
1221. Battle of Indas 1221, right? Let
me let me just quickly check the date.
Battle of Indas
1221, right? It was 1221. Yeah. So this
happened
in 1221
and it was a decisive Mongol victory by
Chingis Khan over Jalaluduin Mangabuni.
So Changis Khan, Shri Chingghistan
defeats
Jalaluduin the coward and
he he captures Jalaluduin's family onto
Raj including Jaladuin's mother and
whoever else maybe his wives and
Jalaluduin the coward jumps into the
river with his horse and crosses the
river and escapes into India
1221 AD and Ching Khan says to hell with
him I'm not going to pursue him I have
no intention of entering India Yeah. And
he goes back because Jaludin is is no
longer relevant. He has been defeated.
If what would have happened if Chingist
Khan had crossed the river.
If Chinghan would have crossed the
river, that would have been the
beginning of an invasion of India. Now,
Chingist Khan did not do invasions for
for for
money, for plunder. He did invasions
only when there was a just cause for an
invasion. which is why he did not invade
India. But if let's say if he had
invaded India, he would have then fought
the Delhi Sultanat. Uh it was ruled by
Iltmish at the time. He would have
defeated Ilutmish in the Delhi Sultanate
and then he would have taken control of
various parts of India, northern India,
I would suppose. If that had happened,
would we have never been colonized by
the Muggles or the Brit or the Brits?
So when did the Muggles start invading
India? Because see eventually the Mongol
Empire disintegrates. Jingghish Khan
dies. His son comes to power. His son
dies. His son comes to power. Eventually
the empire becomes so big it fragments
and then eventually it within 150 years
or so it's no longer a major force.
Right? It becomes so big it's it its
success ended its its relevance
eventually. Um
so if India had been under Mongol uh
rule for a while what would have
happened? Eventually the Mongol rule
would have ended or maybe the Indian
part of the Mongol Empire, Mongol Empire
would have become an independent kingdom
in its own right and in that case would
uh Baba have been able to invade India.
When did Baba invade India? Okay. Uh
when did Zahirin
Babar invade India?
um 1519. So that's 300 plus 300 years
after the battle of Indas essentially.
Uh would the Indian component of the
Mongol Empire still be powerful? There's
no way of saying. So it's totally
hypothetical. I have no idea what would
have happened. If they had still
remained strong, maybe they would have
defeated Zahiruhan Baba and maybe Nester
would have turned out differently. Britz
that's even later I can't really say.
Sloita say okay no no no question well
thank you so much sir slowa great name
good to see you a scorpion king says
what religions would thrive during the
space age Christianity may struggle due
to being too earth humanentric do you
think Indian religion ideas will spread
more as humans spread in space whoever
wins the space race their religion will
will will succeed
and
looks like it's going to be the west
that wins the space race you Musk,
SpaceX, they are way ahead of everybody
else. So soon the Americans will will
have a colony or maybe colonies on the
moon and eventually on Mars. India is
not even participating in the space
race. The Chinese are too far behind.
The Russians are also quite far far
behind. The US, let's say it wins the
space race. It's going to be their
culture, their religion, their religion
that propagates through space. Why will
they ever
spread Indian religion, Hinduism? Why
they hate Hinduism? Why do they hate
Hinduism? Because Hinduism has still not
been defeated.
They'll be more favorably inclined
towards religions that they have
destroyed and defeated in the past.
That's why they talk nice things about
Zorastrianism. Not really. Or or or the
Japanese religion, Shinto or Buddhism.
They say nice things about religions and
cultures they have destroyed. India
still exists. Hinduism still exists.
That's why they hate it. they will not
spread Indian religious ideas uh across
space unless India is defeated and
vasalized and broken up. In that case if
Hinduism is made to
if Hinduism is essentially made extinct
by them then they will then digest ideas
from Hinduism and and maybe spread that
spread that in the future only if
Hinduism is destroyed otherwise they
won't ever do that. So uh what religions
would thrive during the space age? Only
Abrahamic religions. If the west wins in
the extremely unlikely chance that India
wins that will happen if India is a
different entity than what it is right
now. If today's India wins then you they
will India will spread secularism in
space.
Yeah. So it doesn't look like Hinduism
will spread in space. The way things are
going the way India is going India has
zero ambition in space and India is a
this secular nation which rejects its
own civilizational roots and origins
which denies its civilizational roots so
doesn't look like Hinduism is going to
spread in space of course I would like
it to but let's be practical and
realistic
as says your thoughts on India finally
somebody asked me a question about the
trade deal after more than an hour
okay
um what are my thoughts on the India US
interim trade deal. I read many articles
on it. I did not find anything about
India not going to buy Russian oil.
Well, that's the controversy, isn't it?
First of all, what are my thoughts on
the trade deal? Is it a fair balanced
trade? See, first of all, it's not a
trade deal. It's an interim framework.
Uh let's let's see what the minister
Sahab says once again. Mr. Poy, what did
he tweet out about this? Let's see. Um
okay under the decisive leadership of
Prime Minister Narendra Modi GI India
has reached a framework for an interim
agreement with the US. It's a framework
for an interim agreement. So it's not a
trade deal. It's not even an interim
trade deal. It's a framework for an
interim agreement.
Framework for interim agreement. That's
what it is. Now um the question once
again is u is it does it have anything
about not buying Russian oil? Uh if you
look at this joint statement that P go
has tweeted out I could not see anything
any reference to Russian oil it's two
pages
and uh there is absolutely nothing in
the statement put out by P Go about
Russian oil. Absolutely nothing about
Russian oil whatsoever. But here's the
deal and by the way here's the deal. So
there's this uh
there's this u executive order put out
by the US president Shri Trump G and
there's this white house uh statement
over here modifying duty is to address
threats to the US by the government of
the Russian Federation. So if you look
at this so this was uh this came out on
February 6
go's uh statement came out on February
7. So this came out one day before PJ
Go's tweet
and if you go to sector section four of
whatever this is monitoring and
recommendations it says the white house
statement says the secretary of commerce
of the US in coordination with the
secretary of state of the US and the
secretary of treasury and any other
senior official the secretary of
commerce deems appropriate shall monitor
whether India resumes directly or
indirectly importing Russian Federation
oil as defined in section 7 of executive
order 1414329. time. If the Secretary of
Commerce finds that India has resumed
directly or indirectly importing Russian
Federation oil, the Secretary of State
in consultation with the Secretary of
the Treasury, the Secretary of Commerce,
the Secretary of Homeland Security, the
US Trade Representative Representative
Darth Vader and everybody else
uh shall recommend whether and to what
extent I Donald Trump should take
additional action as to India including
whether I should reimpose the additional
advalor rate of duty of 25%. % on
imports or of articles of India. So the
joint India US statement says nothing
about Russian oil. But then this
statement by the white house says that
they will monitor whether India has
resumed purchasing Russian oil either
directly or indirectly. So this is pure
arm twisting.
The interim framework for the interim
trade whatever arrangement between India
and the US has put out in the joint
India US statement tweeted by minister P
go has nothing about Russian oil but
separately the Americans are imposing
these conditions these essentially arm
twisting conditions on India
and then when minister PJ go asked about
Russian oil he I think he said asked the
minister of external affairs Dr.
Jashankar when Dr. Jashen was asked I
think he said ask P go about Russian
oil. So it looks like the government of
India is in a tough spot.
Uh the statements put out by the two
nations
about the trade interim framework trade
thing. There's nothing about Russian
oil. But Trump tweeted something the
other day that India has committed to
not buy Russian oil. So it looks like
India has not agreed to this but the
Americans are now postpacto
insisting that India should not buy
Russian oil otherwise once again the
whole thing is off.
So they are introducing this Russian oil
requirement not buying Russian oil
through the back door or through the
front door or whatever and uh if India
doesn't accept what the Americans saying
then this trade agreement once again
framework will again be washed out of
will will
not be implemented. So the Americans
have arm twisted India. They are in the
process of armresting India and India
now has a very tough choice whether we
accept this US demand that we no longer
buy Russian oil
or we lose this interim framework for
this interim trade agreement. What
should India do if India accepts
American demands for whether we buy
energy or not from a third party? That
is the beginning of the slippery slope
towards becoming a US vasal.
In my opinion, India will most likely
agree to US demands.
What is the rational the logic behind
this? The logic for India accepting this
horrible American demand is that this
Russian oil comes through tankers that
that come from the North Sea. Okay. Uh
where's the map? I'll show you the map.
The Russian oil whether it is direct or
indirect, it comes from where? Okay. It
comes from the North Sea then okay over
here uh into the Atlantic Ocean then
through Gibralar into the Mediterranean
Sea then all the way to Sis
into the Red Sea through the straight of
Babal Mandeb into the Gulf of Aden and
into the western Indian Ocean into India
that's how we are acquiring the Russian
oil mostly
then the Americans if they want they can
choke this off. They can choke it off
through military uh action. They can do
that. So anyway, even if India doesn't
accept this, the Americans can still
choke off this Russian oil. So maybe
India should just give up and accept the
American demand. But if you do that, the
Americans will sense blood and they'll
now start insisting on other things
slowly, step by step. And that is the
slippery slope towards becoming an
American vasal. And that's why I keep
saying there is a significant
non-trivial probability that in the next
5 years India will become a US vasal. I
hope it doesn't happen of course but the
probability of becoming vasal is higher
than not becoming vasal in the next 5
years. The next 5 years are make or
break for India and you can see that
right now in action.
Okay. Moan Sharma says thank you. Love
listening to you. Thank you so much sir.
Thank you indeed. Can you talk about
pre-Abrahamic religions and cultures
across the world map and please share
book references authentic
on the same pre-Abrahamic religions and
cultures across the world. Well, we can
do a world tour. Is that what you're
suggesting? Let's see.
Okay, let's let's look at the big
regions of the world. Pre-Arabic
religions in India. Obviously we had the
various uh indigenous forms of what we
uh of what we call Hinduism which
includes all the various dharmic pants
like Charvaka, Mimmansa, Vidanta, Bodha,
Jana, this that everything all of that.
So that is the subcontinent. All of it
was Indic. It was all Hindu. Even Persia
was Hindu before Zurastianism. Okay. And
even Central Asia was Hindu before
Buddhism. What about China? China had
their own u u taoism and confucianism
and eventually Buddhism which was also
well it was a form of Hinduism because
India did not merely export Buddhism to
China. India exported Hinduism as well.
It was done by Emperor Kaneshka.
It is Kaneshka who who who exported
Indian culture wholesale to China. And
Kaneska
only less than 1% of his coinage has
Buddhist iconography. the rest is all
Hindu or other gods. So, uh, so China
was, you could say, polytheistic. So was
Southeast Asia. After around 1,00 BC,
Southeast Asia became Hinduized for a
for the very long for a very long time.
Uh, Japan, Shinto, eventually Shinto
plus Buddhism.
Uh, what is now Russia, all these
territories, polytheistic cultures,
Mongolia, you had Tangism. Tangism, it's
called Tangorism. It's it's a
polytheistic uh uh system. Once again,
you have the sky father Tangri, the
earth mother Umi, and all kinds of local
gods and goddesses, forest spirits, the
spirits of your ancestors and so on. So
very polytheistic in nature. Mongolia
and the Turk religion originally was
also just like the religion of the
Mongols. Same culture. Um in Siberia,
you had various polytheistic faiths.
Okay.
uh in central Asia you had Hinduism then
Buddhism and then eventually it became
Abraham you have Islam now in Europe you
had various uh local manifestations of
the old Indo-Uropean religion okay which
is well originally Hinduism in Greece
you had Greek polytheism which again is
very similar to Hindu Hinduism in Italy
you had Roman polytheism which absorbed
a lot of Greek elements in Saudi Arabia
you had you had their own version of
polytheism. Okay. In Mesopotamia
once again you had various polytheistic
practices like you know the worship of
goddess Itar Inana
uh various Bal gods and so on. In Africa
you had African polytheisms which are
all wiped out. Uh
what else? What else? In Australia you
had yeah the the indigenous Australian
religion which I am not very familiar
with but again polytheistic in nature.
Um in the Americas you had various
indigenous polytheistic faiths right and
that's kind of a world tour from the
pre-Abrahamic religious and cultural
perspective. Book references I'm not
really sure about book references. Uh I
haven't done all my reading from books.
I do a I'm sure I've studied a lot of
research papers and whatnot. Uh book
references I'm not sure if I can give
you right now off the top of my head.
I'm very bad at giving book book
references unless I prepare in advance
because I've got so many books mixed up
in my head. I can't give you on the spot
book references.
Sorry for that.
Okay. Sort of says, "Why does the
universe allow consciousness?
How does dead matter wake up?" Well, see
there are two big mysteries that you are
that you are synthesizing over here. The
one my first mystery is the mystery of
life and the second mystery is the
mystery of consciousness. How do you
define life?
Living versus non-living. What's the
boundary? What's the definition? I mean
take take viruses for example. Viruses
have characteristics of non-living
beings, non-living things, but they also
have characteristics of living things.
Viruses are like crystals. They don't
they don't achieve homeostasis with
their environment. They don't achieve
equilibrium with the with their
environment
or do they? They probably do actually.
So they have uh elements they have
characteristics of of non-living things
but they also have DNA or RNA which is
very very much a characteristic of
living things. So we don't quite sure
exactly where the dividing life line
between life and non-life exist, right?
What is the dividing line? That's also
kind of gray area. Now consciousness,
you're asking a great question. Why does
the universe allow consciousness? Well,
to answer this question from this
question from a scientific perspective,
I must first define what I mean by
consciousness,
right? I need to have a clear
unambiguous definition of consciousness.
Then we can talk about it from a
scientific perspective. But what is the
definition of consciousness in science?
Do we have a clear definition of
consciousness from a neuroscience
perspective? We don't. Do we have a
clear definition of consciousness from a
physics perspective? We don't. Do we
have a clear definition of consciousness
from a information theory perspective?
We don't. We don't have a scientific
definition of consciousness. Let's say I
have a black box inside which there is a
consciousness. How do I define the
characteristics of this consciousness?
I don't know.
We don't have a scientific definition of
consciousness. So we can't discuss
consciousness without delving into areas
like philosophy and spirituality.
You can't. It's not a scientific
discussion at all. Now why does the
universe allow consciousness? Well, if I
had the answer, I would be one of the
gods. I don't have the answer. We don't
know. We don't know how does dead matter
wake up.
Um
we don't know.
These are big mysteries.
How do you animate that dead matter? I
mean we know that you know in the very
early uh history of the earth at some
point we had the emergence of life you
know microorganisms
um strotholytes possibly or whatever it
was about
3.7 or 3.8 8 billion years before today
possibly perhaps. How did that happen?
Yeah, it's because you had the
you had cell walls and you had DNA. Now
where did DNA come from? These are big
mysteries. You see, so we don't have the
answer as to why does the universe allow
consciousness? If I could give that
answer, well, I deserve more than Nobel
Prize. More than a Nobel Prize and so
on. So these are these are these are
mysteries that science cannot answer at
this point in time.
Sagnik Achara says it seems we have to a
small extent bent the need to the
superpower US via trade deal. If that is
true is semiconductor something we
should focus solely solely focus on for
the next 10 years and get maximum
benefits out of US relations.
Look, when you have
an agreement or or an interim framework
for an agreement between two nations
where one is way more powerful than than
the other, then the agreement is going
to be unequal. Okay? The more powerful
nation will get the better part of the
deal.
That is natural. I mean, look at the
tariffs that the US has imposed on
various nations.
It's imposing 18% on India but other
nations are getting 19 20 25 whatever.
So we are actually getting the the one
of the best deals the Americans have
given anybody. But of course it's
unequal. No question about it.
They say reciprocal 18% but I think
there's more tariffs on India than than
on the US.
That's just the way things are. You
can't expect a completely equal balanced
agreement between India and the US. It's
impossible. We live in the real world. I
think it's it's a good deal overall.
It's the best deal one could get. But
now the Americans are introducing new
conditions via the back door about not
purchasing Russian oil and the Indian
government seems to be really
uncomfortable about this and they don't
know what to say. So that's where we
are. Dilemma for India. Uh if we accept
that it's kind of walking us first steps
down the slippery slope towards be
becoming a vas possibly right. I hope
it's not true. Um so to a to a small
extent we have kind of a little you know
given given in a little bit to the US
but it's still a good good framework
overall. Yeah I am sure there's a lot of
criticism being being heaped upon the
government of India for this right now.
I don't think it's actually legitimate
and valid. One of the issues that's
happened is that Trump has heaped so
many insults on India that any deal that
he gives is going to be regarded with a
lot of suspicion. Trump has said so many
lies that nobody trusts him. These are
the issues, right? When you have a
president like Trump. Uh so yeah, now if
this is true, is super semiconductor
something we should solely focus on for
the next 10 years and get maximum
benefits out of US relations? The US
will give you nothing when it comes to
semiconductors. They will not give you
any technology whatsoever. They want to
extract from India, not give to India.
If the trade deal is somewhat
unbalanced, it means the US is
extracting more than we can extract from
them. Why will they give us some benefit
in semiconductors? Why? Why we should we
I I I totally agree that we should focus
on u developing semiconductor technology
but we will get no benefit from the US
when it comes to this technology. We'll
have to develop it entirely on our own.
Okay. There's no free lunches in the
world my friends nothing. So we're going
to have to develop it on our own and we
we are capable of that. We have s
certain massive barriers to overcome
like uh portal lithography machine
technology and all that but you got to
do the work. You've got to do it.
Gora TV says, "What similarities do you
draw between the Roman Empire and the
United States of America? And do you see
China as Carthage in some way?" Well,
car the people of Carthage allegedly
used to sacrifice children. I don't
think the Chinese do any of that. So,
okay. But, but yeah. Okay. Um,
similarities between the Roman Empire
and the United States of America. Well,
all empires are the same,
the same characteristics. They're
hegemonic.
The Romans,
they practiced two, they practiced two
forms of hedgemony. One is territorial
hedgemony.
They practiced two forms of what?
They they they the Romans wielded power
in two ways. Okay.
One was territorial by by capturing the
territory
of various uh kingdoms and peoples. The
second was by vasalizing
kingdoms without actually capturing
territory.
Okay. So these are the two things the
Romans did. But mostly it was by
capturing territory and actually
occupying the territory physically. The
Americans have also done that and that's
that's how they've expanded their nation
so much by capturing so much territory
that belong to the indigenous people.
First of all the native Americans then
the French then the Mexicans and so on.
That's how they've built up such a big
nation but the majority of their power
is through
versalizing other countries. So there
are similarities, there are differences
and so on, but overall both are empires.
The Rome Roman Empire was an empire. The
US is the current major empire. So yeah,
you can drill down and see so many other
similarities. Uh how do do I see China
as Carthage in some way? No, I don't see
China as Carthage. Carthage actually
struck at Rome. Hannibal Barka invaded
Rome.
Okay. And he defeated the Romans in
various battles including the battle of
Kana. Was it battle of Kana in which he
decimated
um Roman legions? Uh battle of Canai.
Canai.
Uh second Punic War. Who fought the
battle? On the one hand you had Hannibal
Barka.
Where do Hannibal
Hannibal and Yeah.
So Carthage won and this happened in
Italy on Roman territory which means the
the Carthaginians invaded Rome and
defeated them on their own territory.
You think the Chinese are capable of
doing that to the US? No, they're not.
So I don't see China as Carthage in some
way. I don't.
Ganapati says Manurian candidate Modi
the new Mir Jaffer
has sold India to the Anglo under a
subsidiary alliance complete and
unconditional support unconditional
surrender to the US. He has been a US
asset who was grown through something.
Uh I don't agree with this.
He has
sold India to the Anglos really. So
you're talking about the trade trade
interim trade framework or whatever. A
lot of people are saying this. I don't
agree with that. I don't agree complete
and unconditional support surrender to
the US. I don't think so. Yeah, I
disagree. It's a good trade trade
framework or whatever. Of course, the US
will bring in additional terms and
conditions because they are the way more
powerful nation.
And you can't blame Modi for that. Can
you blame Modi for the US being 25 times
more power than powerful than India? He
didn't blame Modi for that. Did Modi
make the US that powerful?
He did not. Right. US asset and all.
Look, I I I disagree with these things.
Okay. Soldier boy says, "Please take my
question from your compost."
Right now, we are only doing super
chats. So, right now, it won't be
possible because I will have to go and
dig up some stuff from God knows where.
uh right now that's not possible but in
the future I I'll try and look it up and
maybe I can take it in the new in the
next live stream where you have asked u
that are in which I pick questions from
the comments right now won't be possible
this is only super chat today all right
sir
Gora TV says despite the US defeating
USSR by infiltrating so deeply into the
Soviet Russian system how did they fail
to prevent Putin's rise to power
they misunderestimated Putin as George W
Bush would say they misunderestimated
Putin. They thought he's just another
bureaucratic kind of guy, you know. So
the Americans were very were very happy
with Boris Yelson, the drunkard.
He stumb he he dragged the US he dragged
Russia down horribly. Um lost the first
Chuchchin war. It was a disaster. And
then
so the US so so Yelin was essentially an
American agent. Okay. and Yelin approved
Putin coming to power. So the and Putin
had this track record of being this
boring
bureaucratic kind of person who just
took orders who did not ever take any
real leadership roles. Putin was just a
just a guy who carried out orders and he
was really good at that. He was a really
efficient administrator but always under
someone's leadership. So that's why
Putin was chosen that okay he's going to
be the next yes man for the US and he's
a great brilliant executor of orders.
That's what they imagined. So that's why
Putin was approved and Putin turned out
to be something entirely different.
Yeah. So the Americans misunderestimated
Putin. They thought he'll be another yes
man. Turned out to be the exact opposite
and good for Russia. I would say good
for Russia. K23040 says Bangladesh
elections are coming up in a few days.
If Jamaat were to win, how would it
affect India in the long run? Great
increase illegals in West Bengal.
Look, Bangladesh is now East Pakistan.
If Jamaat wins, Bangladesh will remain
East Pakistan. Makes no difference. At
this point in time, it doesn't matter
who wins the election in Bangladesh.
Bangladesh is now a US vasal. And
whoever wins the next election will
continue to do whatever the Americans
want them to do. If Jamaat wins or
somebody else wins, it makes no
difference to us.
So in India we have this habit of of
obsessing over Pakistan and Bangladesh
and analyzing things deeply
it makes no difference who wins.
Bangladesh is now an American vasal and
they will do whatever the Americans tell
them. Jamaat or no Jamaat that's the
thing um will jamat winning increase
illegals in West Bengal?
No matter who wins, if we control our
borders,
then the illegals will not come into
India. Right? I don't blame Jamaat or
Bangladesh for the illegal infiltration
into India. I blame us.
I blame the government of India and
paramilitary forces on the borders
for the illegal infiltration of
Bangladeshes into India. Who is in
charge of uh safeguarding India's
borders with Bangladesh? I expect it
should be the border security force,
right? BSF which is not the Indian army.
It's a paramilitary force. What is a
paramilitary force? It's a police force.
So BSF is not Indian military. It's not
Indian army. It's a paramilitary force
and they have I believe been in charge
of safeguarding our borders with
Bangladesh, patrolling our borders. So
the government of India needs to look
into needs to introspect
how come so many Bangladesh are in
India. In 2016 Shri Kiran Riu had said
in parliament that there are about 20 20
million illegal Bangladeshi infiltrators
in India. That's two 2016 10 years ago.
How many do we have today? Why is it so
easy for Bangladeshes to enter India? So
I don't blame Bangladesh or Jamaat or
whoever for that. India is to blame.
India's government is to blame. How many
illegals have been deported back into
Bangladesh the past decade? I wonder
what are we up to really.
Rohani says thanks for all you do. The
streets will never forget forget you.
Thank you so much sir. Thank you so
much.
Mkhov says I'm 18. I've always loved
math but did not get good scores. The
school's way step marking etc. I took it
personally. It hurt my ego. Okay. I
started avoiding it out of fear of
failure or to protect my ego. This
hardwired my brain for a decade. I badly
want to reverse this. How do I do it?
You know some of the best mathematicians
historically
did not get good scores in exams in
mathematics.
Because if you want to be a real
mathematician, let's say
what does a real mathematician do? A
real mathematician has to
take a big problem problem and break it
down into its components and then you
need to have this long chain of thought.
You to sustain that in your brain or or
on paper and it's a long process of
solving big mathematical problems. To
get good marks in school, you to small
to solve the small problems,
right? Uh so if you get got bad marks or
whatever in school, it doesn't mean you
will not be good at mathematics.
Uh if you got bad marks in school, it
means that maybe some fundamentals were
not right for you. So you need to go
back and revisit those fundamentals.
Mathematics actually if you do the
fundamentals right step by step by step
if you do it that way it's the easiest
subject in the world.
So you want to re reverse this thing the
of of you know this fear of failure of
mathematics. How do you do it? You do it
by going back to the fundamentals and
basics.
If you so let's say you are you last
studied mathematics let's say at college
level. Okay, but you want to revisit
mathematics and you are you want to get
overcome this fear of failure and all
that. What you do is you go back to your
maybe eighth certain mathematics and
build your knowledge and and skills all
the way up from that level onwards.
Maybe wherever it is that you have a
deficiency that's what you do and then
you will find that it's easy to do
mathematics once you start building up
the skills and and concepts step by step
you'll find it's easy and that fear of
failure will disappear. So you have to
revisit the root cause of where the fear
came from and you confront the fear head
on. Lock eyes with the fear with the
thing that caused the fear and and and
get rid of that. So that's how you do
it. You will not be able to get rid of
fear by avoiding the thing that that
scares you. You've got to lock horns
with it and you've got to dismantle it.
That's how you u reverse the fear of
failure.
Gapati says in 2016 ISRO budget was $1
billion. FCST budget was $9 billion. In
2026, ISRO's budget is $1.6 billion.
SCST budget is $40 billion. I no longer
feel obligated to serve this raashtra.
I understand how you feel. I'm not sure
if I don't know if these figures are
correct. I'm not sure where you got them
from. They may possibly be I'm not sure
what is the SCST budget tax actually.
But um yeah, I I I understand what
you're trying to say and obviously it is
dispiritating. It is discouraging
and I I I feel you. I feel you.
Amisha says why no minister is giving
clarity on Russian oil? That's a good
question.
Who are the ministers concerned in this?
It is Shri Push Goyel and Shri Dr.
Jashankar. These are the two ministers.
Um Sharif Goyel what what is his
ministry is trade right commerce
minister of commerce and industry so
that's that obviously is the ministry
which will be engaged in negotiations
with the US to hammer out an interim
framework for an interim trade deal
and the other ministry obviously is the
foreign ministry Dr. Jashankar now both
have been asked about Russian oil so
first of all the Indian prime minister
tweeted this the Mr. Go tweeted this.
There was no statement about Russian oil
whatsoever
concerning this interim framework for
this interim trade deal with the US. So
it looks like India has been caught by
surprise by this America by the
Americans springing a trap on India.
Right?
And then when Mr. PJ go was asked he
said please refer this question to the
foreign ministry. When Dr. Jashen was
asked he said please refer the question
to the commerce ministry. So it looks
like there is a lack of clarity. India
has been caught unawares apparently.
So the question so the answer as to why
no minister is giving clarity is
probably because we have not reached a
decision yet. It probably means the
government of India has not has been
caught unawares. It has been surprised.
It has been ambushed by the Americans.
Maybe the Americans gave asurances and
then after giving asurances they sprang
sprung this sprang the trap on India. So
a decision now has to be made by the
government of India probably by the
prime minister of India and until the
decision is taken probably no clarity
will come out. So if no minister is
given clarity right now it means that
the decision has not been taken most
likely. Most likely not 100% sure but
most likely. So it looks like we don't
know right now what decision we're going
to take but eventually we're going to
have to take a decision either we accept
the American demand the arm twisting
which will embolden the Americans for
making more demands now or we resist and
say no which means this trade deal gets
torn up and thrown into the waste bin
but how can you do that when you have
celebrated already
the government of India has been this in
this celebratory code
we have achieved this great fantastic
thing. Now if you say no to the Russian
Russian oil thing then the Americans
will say that Modi has sabotaged the
trade deal that will be a disaster
politically which means you have to
accept the trade deal but the trade deal
now comes with this condition which
wasn't there earlier of not buying
Russian oil anymore. So looks like India
is going to have to agree to this
American arm twisting demand of not
buying Russian oil which will impact our
relationship with Russia potentially.
That's where India stands. So are we
going to start walking down the slippery
slope towards Basalhoud is the question.
Vihang Kuran says uh for a student
serious about AI and research does an
MTech or MS in AI
from IIT's IS provides strong value
today or is going abroad clearly better
thank you for creating the history
course I thoroughly enjoyed you very
welcome so you are serious about AI and
research
and the question you have is do I do an
MTech or MS in AI from I IT or Indian
Institute of Science
or should I do it from should I do it
going abroad?
My answer to you is very simple.
Do not
look if you can afford going abroad, you
should definitely go abroad. But if
you're not go abroad, if you would to
take this horrible loans and it will
ruin your family's finances. If that is
the case, see most people
for most people to go to the US or
abroad, you need to take big loans that
you can't afford and then you have to
keep paying them paying these loans for
loans for years or decades. If that is
the case, I would say don't do that. But
if you can afford going abroad, you
should choose going abroad because you
will get better value in a nation like
the US for example doing research in AI
AI compared to
even the top Indian institutes.
So going abroad as long as it's a a
highquality US college or university is
clearly better. That is my honest
opinion and honest recommendation but
only if you can afford it. Don't destroy
your feminist finances because that's a
problem right. So yeah all the best we
all the best to you sir all the best.
Moan Sharma says thanks love listening
to you. Thank you so much sir. Could you
talk about prehabraic cultures and
religions across the world? Okay I I did
do this right. I think this question is
repeated somehow but uh yeah uh we I
just took this a while ago. Yeah. Uh
Raki Ganwani says, "Thank you, sir, for
understanding new subat." Thank you so
much, Raki G and welcome to this
channel. Thank you very much.
Pratib Kumar Roy says, "There's a statue
of Enlil Enlil in the Epstein island,
ancient Mesopotamian Mesopotamian god.
He was also known as Baal or Yahweh that
accepted child sacrifices. Jews claim
not to worship Malik.
So this god Malik, this entity called
Malok was allegedly a god
that that the Canonites worshiped.
Maybe it was a form of Yahweh or
whatever. I'm not very sure about that.
But the the Hebrew Bible claims alleges
that the Canonites used to worship this
creature called Yahweh. Sorry, not
Yahweh. a Moolok. And Moolok was
associated with associated with child
sacrifices.
And the descendants of the Canonites
were the were the were the Phoenicians
who set up Carthage and they allegedly
they also did child sacrifices in in
Carthage at the Tophet. And you actually
find evidence of that like large
quantities of evidence of that sort of
thing. So, I don't know who this Enlil
god is, but uh yeah, this Epstein thing.
So, look, the Canonites,
they date back to maybe 1,000 BC or
something, right? Maybe before that.
So, looks like in their culture,
in this western culture, this has been
kind of happening behind the scenes for
at least 3,000 years. this all the
gutliness associated with the Epstein
island, this pedophilia, this this
eating of babies and oh god knows what
kind of horrific things are coming out
of this. This is your western culture.
Okay.
Gapati says Israeli tourists were caught
starting wildfires in Argentina.
Israeli tourists are also flooding
Himach Pradesh ever since natural
calamities like fires, flood floods,
landslides have increased. Okay, I am
not aware of this.
I'm not aware of this.
So, okay.
But yeah, I have not heard of these
things.
Edmmo Dante. Oh, you have been reading
the account of Monteto, have you? Edmmo
Dante. Well, I am very pleased for Edmma
Donte because he did eventually get his
revenge.
So, biblical Helodorus sent to Sucus IV
to loot temple treachery is struck down
by angels.
Decades later, there's a Vishnu pillar
erected in Bhat by Heliodoris.
A wild coincidence. What are my
thoughts? I
have no thoughts about this. I am not
aware of this. Who was the biblical
Heliodoris? Let's see. Uh biblical
biblical
Helodorus.
Doris. Who was biblical Heliodoris?
2nd century BC salucid chancellor under
King Salucas IV Filipoper. Okay. Known
from two Makabe 3 for his failed attempt
to rob the temple in Jerusalem
and so on. Okay. Uh now pillar.
So this is the what u century BC. Okay.
Okay. Now pillar ofodorus.
So where is this from? This is 113 BC.
Oh, fascinating. That's the second
century BC. And this guy was from the
second century BC.
Fascinating. Is this the same guy?
That's really interesting. Heliodoris
minister. It looks like this is a
different person. Yeah, maybe the name
Heliodoris may have been a common name
at the time among the Seucid people. The
Salucids were Greeks of course. So maybe
it was a common common name you know
like John. John is a very common name
right in in among the Christians. Um is
this a coincidence? Wild coincidence?
Maybe it's a coincidence. Clearly this
seems to be like two different people,
right? Looks like it's two different
people. Probably not the same person.
uh because a Vishnu pillar being erected
by a heliodoras clearly that person was
a civilized person dharmic person they
would not go and loot the uh treasury of
the temple of the Jews right and he was
in India Judea was way way way to the
west it's not like he could hop onto a
plane or a helicopter and go to Judea
and return right so probably different
people
says how just 150,000 British were able
to rule over 300 million Indians. What
structural, religious or social factors
made this possible? It happened over
time. So the British,
how were they able to succeed where the
uh Spaniards and the Portuguese could
not? So the British were great at
controlling trade routes. They were
great at controlling ports and doing all
that. But they also did things that the
Portuguese and the Spaniards did not. is
that they instituted bureaucracies and
used bureaucracies to control nations.
They knew how to divide
and create fissures
among nations among the people of the
nation that they were targeting and
slowly over time take control. So the
British arrive in India when 1600 1610
right that's when they set up their fort
in Surat and they finally take over
India in the 1800s
right 18 when was the second Anglo
Maratha war when does it end uh second
Anglo Maratha war
uh that is when 1805 okay so 1610 to
1805 that takes them 200 years
And eventually so it it took them more
than 200 years to start to to to
establish this form of control over
Indians. So their
policy of divide and rule, divide and
conquer plus their incredibly efficient
bureaucracy
in which they co-opted Indians to work
for them. All of these things, you know,
that's what made this possible. So
eventually the Indians were and and of
course the famines, right? They
engineered hundreds of artificial
famines in India. Indians if you are if
you don't have if you can't eat
where will you have the strength to
fight the British. So all these factors
put together allowed the British to rule
Indians and eventually they in this this
mallayian
education system which still continues
right which indoctrinates Indians and
and endows Indians with this deep sense
of inferiority that the white man is
better than us. Malik Malik sahib right
then Indians will
will will obey orders like dogs obey
humans. So these are the things lots of
these factors came together. The British
were great at this. I mean you have to
admire the the evil
right
I mean in some sense it's admirable what
they were able to do.
Yoshiati says it makes sense
at least for Russians to unmask
individuals of the deep state to
popularize unknowns. Why has it not
happened? Are they afraid of
repercussions?
Look, you can't unmask without proof,
right?
If you want to unmask somebody, you have
to provide proof. Otherwise, you will be
called a conspiracy theorist.
And to provide proof, proof is going to
be hidden. So, you have to to provide
proof, you have to to establish long
chains of evidence that most people will
not have the patience to dig into and
understand.
people who are hidden deep inside. All
these things to uncover them
is not easy because you have to provide
long chains of connections to actually
establish that this person is actually
controlling that or whatever and for the
ordinary human being understanding that
long chain of evidence is impossible
because you need a certain amount of IQ
for that.
So then what you do you keep quiet,
right? That's the thing we hung Quran
says from your experience how can a
student gorge whether they have the
aptitude and temperament required for a
research career how do you do it you you
try researching something you try taking
on a research project at whatever level
you are so let's say you are at the uh
in India what they call the
undergraduate level bachelor's degree
level right right let's say you are in
physics or mathematics you try and solve
a problem
maybe
a problem that's already been solved but
you try and solve it your own in a
different way
let's say if you are in mathematics
uh try and derive the m Mclloren series
from scratch a priority from first
principles what is the Mclloren series
beautiful
okay
beautiful I mean
Mathematics is beautiful, right? If you
see the Mclloren series and if you
understand what this says, you can see
how beautiful mathematics is. So how do
you derive this from scratch or
something else? How do you derive how do
you prove how do you derive the Taylor
series expansion from scratch? You try
and do these things and see if you are
able to do it. If you're able to do
these things, you will know that maybe
you have the aptitude for research. So
how do you understand whether you have
the aptitude and temperament research
required for research? by trying these
things out and see if you enjoy it or
see if it is painful for you. Right?
That's how you find out. Okay. All the
best. Gapati says in many of your videos
you treat you you claim that Jews were
never mistreated by India in India. Try
googling Kadavat Achi. Enjoy. This
gentleman seems to be very pleased with
what he is trying to achieve here. Let's
see. Let's see. Let's see. Kadavat Achi.
What is kadavat ai?
Kadavat ai
lady of the riverside.
I am not going to open Reddit links and
and and random blogs.
Oh, legend has it that around 1165 AD
there was a wealthy Jewish widow and
blah. So some kind of legend based on
some rumor. I am not even wasting my
time with this BS. Thank you very much
sir. Please understand what reliable
sources are. Okay come on enjoy.
Bye-bye.
Seriously.
Vive Singh says hi sir do you think it's
a good idea to set up townships for our
public sector unit employees and the
families with all facilities within this
can make them more productive. I am
there with
syrup townships. Do don't you have
townships? I mean you have old townships
where people from government sectors
they all live together in things and
all. This has been tried in India.
This has been tried.
Will it make people more productive? No,
you don't need to do all this to make
people productive. you have to make some
reforms and cut out some of the things
that key that
um
some of the problems which which I don't
mention here. So putting people together
in townships with their families and all
all facilities will that make them more
productive? Not necessarily. This has
been done in India won't make much of a
difference. Loita says what are 10
problems that India should solve
immediately? How to solve India's
education system?
Okay, once again it's a good question.
I'm going to give you references.
So what we do is this.
We go to this YouTube channel.
This one, my YouTube channel that we are
watching right now. We go to the live
tab. We go to oldest
and then we go down.
Now, if you want to solve India's
education system, watch episode 28, 30
and 31 of Askabit.
I have explained everything in the
greatest of detail. This is 4 years ago
it was streamed. it still is 100%
relevant today. That's how you solve
India's education system. Watch those um
three episodes because see the answer is
not something I can give in 5 minutes.
You're going to have to watch those
three episodes to understand what the
problems are and what the solutions what
solutions are required. Okay. Uh 10
problems India should solve immediately.
First I'll give you a few. I don't know
if I can give you 10 m at this point in
time but one is illegal infiltration.
Second is all the illegal infiltrators
who are currently within India they need
to be deported right that um solve what
else the education system obviously
which is a disaster trash garbage
terrible education system. Um
next reservations are fine as long as
they are on the basis of uh economic
condition of families not cast eliminate
cast entirely right that needs to be
fixed. Uh what else? All the all the
alleged corruption that may exist in
India that needs to be dealt with and so
on. There are many such problems.
Okay. Pratip Kumar Roy says about the
four pillars
city of London Washington DC Vatican and
Israel also about white black leader of
Jesuits and gray popes I am not aware of
any of these things um clearly you're
talking about some theories that people
some people may have but I am not aware
of the details so I can't say about that
what is white black leader of Jesuits
great popes I'm not aware of these
things you see there are things that I
also don't know about and I don't know
about this I'm very sorry sorry sir
Gora TV says in a hypothetical scenario
where you are the supreme commander of
India with three which what key
strategic pivots would you prioritize in
your first five years of leadership and
where would you take India if I was in a
hypothetical situation where I am the
supreme commander of India what would I
do first deport all illegals out of
India immediately number one that's what
I would do second I would embark on a
20-year reformation program of the
Indian education system based on what
I've already said in the past that is
critical. Number three, I would hike up
the percentage of the GDP or the budget
that is allocated to defense, right? Uh
that's what I would do. How many things
are these?
Illegals uh GDP defense. Third is uh
education system, right? Uh fourth, I
would try and be as atman as possible. I
I would make India as atundar as
possible. Technologically, we need
technological sovereignty. So I would
focus on AI would focus on
semiconductors that's things we are
doing right now quantum computing and
also the basic stuff right the the
manufacturing that needs to happen in
India ease of doing business very
important next I would end reservations
based on cast I would annihilate cast
completely complete annihilation of cast
the word cast or any cast whatever
references we have in in India's
official documentation whether it is
your birth certificate or a death
certificate or school certificate or
whatever
remove all references to cast and I I
would continue maybe you know
reservations maybe for another 20 years
purely on the basis of a family's
financial condition nothing else and you
can't have reservations forever maybe 20
years maximum right these are some of
the things I would do I would focus on
the Indian space program I would make
India a major participant in the space
race right I would have India build at
least 50 more submarines
I would have India build 300 more naval
assets
apart from the 50 submarines.
These are some of the things I would do
and I would be very very very harsh on
corruption. The harshest you can
imagine.
These are the things I would do. Some of
some of the things yeah Pratep Kumar Roy
says about the 13 families in the crown.
I am not aware of the 13 families sir.
I'm not aware of these. Uh some link
them to ancient Romans. Do they really
controlled everything? Also about the
financial industrial complex, Black
Rockck, Vanguard, and Straits state
street. See, I don't know about these 13
families. I don't know even one of these
families. I haven't studied or read
about this. The crown, which crown?
Which crown? You're talking about the
British crown. Why is that the only
crown? So, yeah, I don't know. Some link
them to ancient Romans. I'm not aware of
that. Do they really control everything?
I'm not aware of that. Financial
industrial complex that does exist. Of
course, Black Rockck, Vanguard,
Vanguard, Street, are they connected to
some ancient families? I am not aware of
that. I'm not aware of these things. I'm
very sorry, but I am not aware of these
things. I haven't studied this or read
about this. So, can't say can't say. I'm
very sorry. Sid Di says India should
allow dual citizenship. model could be
renounce,
live in India again, prove commitment,
regain citizenship, keep foreign one as
well. Indian origin people can also get
dual like that. I will have to
respectfully disagree with this. You can
have dual citizenship, you can allow
dual citizenship only if you are the
global hedgeim.
If you are a weak relatively weak nation
like India, the fourth most powerful
nation, the third most powerful is like
four times more powerful than us. And
the US is like 25 times more powerful
than us.
In that case, the US, if you allow dual
citizenship, the US can infiltrate you
and even the Chinese can infiltrate you
in all kinds of ways.
And uh you'll have people who have dual
citizenship and who are working for the
more powerful and the richer nation.
Even and yeah sure let's say we have
this model you renounce live in India
again prove commitment then you regain
this dual citizenship which nobody will
accept first of all nobody has a time to
do that but even if you did that then
yeah okay live in India prove commitment
for 5 years and then start spying then
what happens
it doesn't work it's not practical
that's my point
a
Avin Shukla has become a new YouTube
member. Your name is super confusing,
sir. But anyway, thank you so much for
becoming a member. I really appreciate
it. Welcome to the channel's membership.
Thank you. Gapati says, "Mother Terresa
was the OD OG Jeffrey Epstein." Well,
yeah. I mean, the things if you want to
learn the truth about this person
Teresa, I have a book recommendation.
See, for for a change, I remember a
book. It's a it's got a really
interesting name. Okay. The missionary
position. The missionary position. Mud
tisa and theory in practice. It's by
Christopher Hitchens.
It was published in 1995.
The missionary position by Christopher
Hitchens in which Christopher Hitchens
exposes this person thoroughly. You see,
you have to if I say it, you won't
believe it. But if a white guy says it,
you'll believe it. Right? So that's why
I'm giving you the this reference from
this book written by a white guy. So now
we'll believe it.
Fields strong man says you have said
Roose won't report actual weapon count
of Sikun. What's a seun? Roose won't
report actual weapon count of Sikun. So
how can we trust the statistics on oil
imports like chin from Iran?
You said 5 to 15%. Can two countries not
have under the table dealing of oil
imports? Of course, you can have it, but
they can still figure it out. There are
ways of figuring things out. There is
something called a black fleet, a shadow
fleet in which you have tankers that
will do refueling in the middle of the
ocean and then put a new flag and then
go and do something. You can still
figure things out. Okay? You can.
You don't have to trust somebody's
numbers and figures and statistics they
put out. You can actually track in real
time every single tanker that's carrying
oil in the ocean and you can see what's
happening where I mean it's possible in
real time. So you don't you don't have
to take anybody at their word but you
can still figure out what's happening.
So that's how you can figure out that
this nation it claims to not purchase
oil from so and so nation but actually
it is doing it indirectly
and yeah that sort of thing. Okay. Dark
Side of the Moon, DSOTM.
That's a great album, isn't it?
How might India incompetent feudal
elites fixated on exploiting only cheap
labor or R&D good infra doit to
geopolitical irrelevance and US was by
insisting that India not doesn't become
technologically sovereign? Let's say you
have a hypothetical scenario in which
you have you know an incompetent feudal
elite bureaucrat or or minister
hypothetically who says India should
never develop sovereign AI models. India
should become a consumer of foreign AI.
India should build application layers on
top of the the base LLMs and whatnot. So
India will should use foreign AI systems
and build applications on top of that.
Well, that's one way of making India
completely irrelevant technologically.
That's one example. There are so many
other examples of other ways of doing
it. So, ensure that India only imports
high-tech items. India doesn't
manufacture or produce any of that.
India should to ensure that India
doesn't do any R&D in in technology,
right? R&D budget keep it very low.
Import all the cutting edge defense
equipment from other countries. Don't
don't fund the jet engine program.
Allocate very small amounts of money to
quantum computing research to AI
research. So many ways of doing it,
right? So that's how you become
geopolitically irrelevant. You become
eventually someone's masal so many ways
of doing it. And all of this put
together dooms you to mediocrity and
massage.
Suhin Rey says, "As a student then as a
student, how can I bring nationalism and
cultural pride?
As a student, as an individual,
how can you be nationalistic and have
cultural pride? By learning about your
nation, by being proud of the
achievements that our ancestors have
had. By being proud of the greatness of
our culture. I mean, today the the
standards are so low, right?
Today we all we have to say that we are
we we don't have a culture of of
pedophilia and cannibalism that's all
the the standards are so low now we are
way above that
so that how can you have other people do
it I'm not sure about that as as as an
individual you can talk to your friends
and family and whatever you learn about
your culture your nation you can share
those ideas and thoughts and and those
facts with your family and with your
friends and that's how you can make them
also gradually feel proud that's what
you can do
okay Pratep Kumar Roy says about the
downfall of Bengal is the left
responsible about the downfall of Bengal
see Bengal
the British they colonized Bengal first
right they occupied Bengal first of all
the regions of India they first set set
down roots in Bengal
and the British wrote about Bengal that
it was the richest province of India
And obviously Bengal has this great
glorious past,
great culture, great kings,
all of that.
So Bengal is to be so great and the
British ruined it thoroughly.
But still if you look at let's say the
year 1940, Kolkata and Harra
were greater than
Mumbai and Chennai put together. That
was then Bombay and Madras.
The population of Kolkata plus Hara was
bigger probably than Bombay and Madras
put together. These are the pop
pre-colonial
the colonial names of these cities.
Right? Today it is Mumbai and Chennai.
So Kolkata was still at the time a major
industrial city.
It was the engine that drove the Indian
economy.
And then look at Kolkata today. who did
this?
So, Kolkata was the engine of Bengal and
of India. Who did this? I suppose it was
the left that de-industrialized Bengal.
So, it's it's been a tragic tragic fall
for Bengal, right? From being one of our
greatest regions to what it is today.
Okay.
Feel strong man says you YouTube is a
YouTube is a sob platform. I spent 22
minutes trying to type the word nuclear.
I hope you don't have this word banned
on your channel. Absolutely not. Why
would I ban the word word nuclear?
It's not a word that's banned on this
channel.
So, well, you tried you spent 22 minutes
trying to type this word.
Uh, what can I say? It's it's a I
there's nothing I can do about that. I'm
sorry that you had this experience.
Yeah, YouTube has its own peculiarities
for sure. Indeed.
Okay. The scorpion king says, "America
is the last religious western nation.
Christianity is collapsing like
zorostranism in the west. This will
hinder Christianity globally as it will
be associated with poor African nations
rather than the west." Well,
Christianity has to survive somehow,
right? So, it will seek new places where
they can poach souls.
They are looking for India. India is the
is one of the major targets for these
Christian converters, isn't it? You have
industrial scale
conversions happening in India in
certain states.
And the government of India is allowing
this to happen blightly
unaware or aware of whatever it is.
Yeah. So yeah, India is a poor nation
similar to many African nations. So
maybe Christianity for a while will be
associated with poor nations. Now unlike
Africa, India will grow economically. So
maybe in 50 years time, India will be
the biggest economy and it'll be a
Christian nation. Then Christianity will
once again be glorious.
Yeah.
So America is the last religious western
nation.
If you look at the European nations, the
western European nations, there's very
little religiousness left there. So
yeah, Christianity is mostly gone. Uh
the US has pockets of Christianity. You
have this very very very uh the MAGA
folks are all Christians aren't they?
And uh you have Mexico which is kind of
Christian to some extent. But yeah major
Christian western nation US. Yeah. So
maybe the next major Christian nation
will be India. Yeah possible.
Namit Rana says as India, China and
Russia only left for Anglos. Will Russia
supply a few nukes to Iran to counter
Egypt Saudi develop nukes? Will it
disrupt Anglo's plan? Okay. Once again,
India, China and Russia are only left
for the left for the Anglo. Well, even
Iran is left. Will Russia supply a few
nukes to Iran?
To counter Egypt? To counter Egypt?
And to counter Egypt, Saudi develop
nukes.
And to counter Egypt, Sa I'm not sure
what is exactly what you're saying.
Okay. The one question I understand is
will Russia supply a few nukes to Iran.
It's unlikely, but not entirely
impossible.
It's unlikely,
but not impossible. Maybe it's one way
to have Iran survive a potential regime
change operation or potential invasion
by the US. It's a dangerous step. Of
course, it will be regarded by the
Americans as a major provocation, but I
suppose Russia could do that, right? If
Russia does that, it will definitely
disrupt the any any plan that the like
you say Anglos may have of invading
Iran. It's a possibility. I think it's
less likely
but not zero percentage likelihood. So
yeah, it's possible possible.
Okay
says PDF alia can be in DNA. What does
science say? I don't know. I have never
studied the science of PDF behavior. So
I have no idea. Can it be in DNA?
I that's a pretty
I I don't know. I I have absolutely no
knowledge of this. I have thankfully
never had to study or research this
stuff. So I don't know what science
says.
I can't say. I'm very sorry.
It's like asking can homosexuality be
there in your DNA? Are some people more
genetically predisposed for
homosexuality? I am not sure. I'm not
sure. I don't know. This is a subject
that's beyond my scope of understanding.
Sorry. Harish Sharma says, "You think
decline of the West Indies cricket could
be because it's not a single country and
feeling of patriotism is not there.
Plus, there's a lot of there are a lot
of issues between the cricket board and
the players." There have been issues
between the cricket board and players. I
remember uh DH Ramdin once uh hit a
century and then put out this you know
he came with this
with this message slogan yay na wave
talk y wave talk n or something and
there have been many issues between the
cricket board and the players the I
think uh Chris Gail had issues with with
the cricket board and
other things again West India is not a
single country it's a bunch of nations
yeah a bunch islands with which lack a
common identity that's been an issue as
well. But look from the 1970s, late '7s
all the way to the early '90s, the West
Indies were invincible despite not being
a single country. So being a single
country or not is not the issue. It's
about the decline of standards in the
players, in the leadership and also on
the cricket board. That's what has
caused the issues with western disc
cricket.
A vi ain shukla says love love love
whatever small contribution you're doing
for the country. Would love to
collaborate and do it 5x using AI visual
medium mailed you Jahind. Okay I'll
check my email. Thank you very much.
Thank you so much once again for the
encouragement
and I'll check out your email. Thank you
very much sir.
Aaron says, "Congress and BJP have
exploited people with unfulfilled
promises. Do you think we can get a new
party which can change the system and
help us be a superpower?"
The first thing I would say is India
should stop using the word superpower in
Vishwaguru for the next 20 years. Now
about these various political parties
with unfulfilled promises, it's
possible. I typically don't comment
about internal domestic politics of
India. uh so I'll not comment about
these unfulfilled promises of various
parties but do I think we can get a new
party which can change the system
well theoretically it's possible in
practice it's next to impossible
cuz forming a new party and actually
gaining power takes years if not decades
it's really really hard and you need a
lot of money for that tremendous amounts
of money really hard very very hard for
for ordinary people to do that. So yeah,
that's the dilemma that India is in now.
Suga Suga R says, "Is it even worth to
get married in 2026 as a man when
everything is stacked against you? Laws
are not protecting you or are even
against you. Look, it is still
worthwhile to get married as long as you
have a person as you have a partner
who's reliable,
who is not someone who will gain the
system and and eventually
throw you under the bus. There are still
good people in the world, right?
There still are good girls, good good
women in the world. You got to find the
right person. Find a p person with the
right values, right? Not somebody who's
a gold digger.
So yeah, it's it's definitely
a little more danger like considerably
more dangerous today as a male
if you end up with the wrong person. You
you stand to lose a lot. But it still is
worth getting married.
Okay? It's it's part of the human
experience that you you got to have.
Marriage is the foundation of society.
The family is the unit of society, not
the individual, unlike what the West
would like you to believe. So you've got
to continue that. You've got to continue
the traditions of our ancestors. You got
to carry on your lineages. So you've got
to do it, but you've got to do it more
carefully. Now it certainly is worth
getting married. So don't get
discouraged. You've got to look for the
right person. And at the at a young age,
it's difficult to find the right person
because you don't have have any
experience of wisdom. for that you may
have to rely on your family perhaps to
help you out with that.
Anyway, yeah, so all the best. Do get
married but to the right person.
Dir Kamat says, "How exactly do the
middle classes and common masses rise up
against the elites bolstered by AI and
genetic engineering transhumanism? Is
there any hope?"
The hope is that
See, when it comes to elites bolstered
by AI and genetic engineering and trans
humanism and all that, we're talking
about the American and Western elites.
What can the middle classes and common
masses of the West do about this?
Precious little,
precious little. The hope is a
non-western culture will rise
and possibly
eventually win
where you don't have elites
who seek to subjugate everybody
where you don't have elites who are PDF
files and cannibals and whatnot.
Right? So hopefully a civilized nation
wins this race, this technological race.
Hopefully. Do we have any civilized
nations around us? I'm not sure but
let's see.
Hanish Sharma says, "Do you did or do
you ever have the interest in visiting
all the countries in the world?" Oh, I
would love to travel across the world
and visit every single country. I love
traveling. Yeah. I'm not sure if I'll
visit all the countries in the world
during this lifetime of mine, but if I
can, I would certainly do that. Yeah.
Okay. Pratik Kumar Roy says someone
mentioned Mother Teresa and Epstein
link. Dark history of Bengal in the
1980s. Last year some doctor died in RG
car. Maybe she knew too much. Modern
Moolok is active through wars and
epidemics it seems.
Yeah, I'm not aware of this doctor who
died in whatever that is. Arjikar,
a lady doctor. She knew too much. Okay,
I don't know about that.
Dark history of Bengal in the 1980s. I
hear that Bengal was the source of this
trade in human skeletons in the 1980s
and there seems to be some Teresa
connection there also perhaps uh there
something came out. Okay. uh
Bengal
1980s
skeleton trade.
Kolkata was the center of a massive
legally murky and eventually illicit
international human skeleton trade.
Kolkata based exporters were the world's
leading suppliers of anatomical
specimens with an estimated 2.4 4
million human skeletons and skulls
exported from India between 1947 and
1985.
Would you believe it?
Officially sourcing unclaimed bodies
from police and hospital morgs. The
massive demand led to the grave robbing
of cemeteries,
bodies being taken for rivers, and god
knows what else was happening.
The industry faced a major scandal in
March 1985 when a trader was arrested
for attempting to export 1,500 child
skeletons.
Okay. So there this and
the missionaries of charity were were
were based in Kolkata was it? There's a
lot of dirt that's been hidden away.
Yeah.
Hyphen says, "If money didn't exist,
what would rich mean?" Well, if money
did not exist, being rich would mean
that you have control over large
quantities of resources, way more than
other people. So, money is
money is
a substitute for resources, isn't it?
With money, you can buy resources. So,
if you did not have money, then being
rich would mean you have control over
resources. That's what being rich would
mean. Resources. What kind of resources?
Maybe land,
land, uh oil, gas, minerals, all of
that. That sort of resources, you know,
human capital and so on.
Gapati says, "Why do many people
associate Hinduism with vegetarianism
especially in the north? Here in Tamil
Nadu we have a p a habit of sacrificing
goats and pigs and offer them to the to
the di and later consumed as prasad.
Well it's it's a long story.
I think it dates back about 2 and a half
thousand years. Before that
there was no compulsion or or any any of
this association of Hinduism with ainsa
and vegetarianism. Then what happened is
Buddhism see both the dharma was
suddenly made into a big thing by
emperor Ashok and then there was this
this uh this competition
for which whether Buddhism becomes
bigger than the other other dharmic
parts. So the practitioners of Buddhism
used to taunt brahinss as animal killers
because you had humans sorry not human
you had animal sacrifice in Hinduism
right obviously various yagnas and whatn
not there are sacrifices of animals.
So brahinss used to be taunted as as
animal killers and evil people and all
by the by Buddhists. So brahinss made
this practical decision that we will
become complete vegetarianis vegetarians
that gives us the upper hand over the
Buddhists because the Buddhists still uh
ate animals but not as much as used to
be that sort of thing. So, so that's why
Brahmans became tactically vegetarians
and that tradition has continued not all
across India but in various parts of
India
and that's how Hinduism got associated
with vegetarianism
but various Hindu communities I mean
they eat meat
and there's nothing about not eating
meat in any of the way I mean at least
in the rigida the rigida I mean the
rigida is the foundation of Hinduism
doesn't say don't eat meat. It says you
cannot kill cows and you can't kill
humans. That's what it says. It doesn't
say you can't eat horse meat. It doesn't
say you can't eat other forms of meat.
It doesn't say that, right? And we have
all these traditions of of sacrificing
various animals. Pashubali it's called,
right? It's definitely a part of
Hinduism. It it makes some people um
uncomfortable. That's okay. It is what
it is. Hinduism is a very broad thing,
right? With so many different practices.
Okay. Sid Dav says, "Have you read the
Quran? Quran claims Alexander the Great
Dulkar was appointed by Allah to build
giant wall to contain evil tribes, Gog
and Magog opinion. I have not the least
understanding of this. I have not read
the the Quran. So I I'm not aware of
this. Um yeah sorry this is beyond my
understanding.
Pratar Dhana says strong China in Russia
India's interest
um strong China is it in Russia's
interest in India's interest
that's that's the dilemma we have today
right neither Russia nor nor India can
trust China
but if China becomes way too weak then
the Americans can then deal with Russia
and India separately
so I think we need some kind of balance
If see how does India prevent itself
from being vasalized in the next 5 years
only it's only possible if India Russia
and China come together in some way and
and together
resist American hgemony individually
these three nations will fall even
Russia can fall
so is a strong China is in Russia's
interest I think a balanced framework of
India Russia China that's what is in
India is India's interest. If China
becomes more powerful compared to the
US, they they will start again their
their nasty behavior along the India
Tibet border. So we need balance. We
don't need a strong China. It's like you
know way too strong.
Um Pratarana says some of us don't
consider the 1857
events as a war of independence. Well,
some of us are wrong. I suppose it was a
war of independence. Some of us yeah
India is so large that some of us won't
consider it to be a war of independence.
Some of us will say it was a revolution
it was a revolt or a mutiny like the
British say. Well those some of us are
wrong. Okay.
Okay. Viki Kana says do you think if
invasion of India happens by the G2
powers what are the G2 powers? US and
China. So if invasion of happen if if
invasion of India happens by G2 powers
if someone thinks to rule will India
launch huge
V for the world poison the seed nuke
others
isn't if we go down this time we will
take the world with us
will India do something nasty I don't
know about uh huge ws poison the sea and
newcomers.
I don't know if the Indian leadership
has the cohes to do that.
Does India have our equivalent of the
Samson option? The Samson option is the
Israeli u you know doomsday scenario
that if is if Israel goes down they will
take all the enemies down by launching a
devastating nuclear strike or strikes.
The Americans also have something like
this that if America is going under in a
nuclear attack, the Americans will nuke
every single country. That matters and
take the whole world down with them.
Does India have a similar plan or
strategy? I don't know. I don't know.
Maybe India says that if we go down, we
will not take the world down with us. I
don't know about that. It's a I mean
that's that's I mean it's it's terrible
to even even imagine these things. But
so
what does India do? I suppose India
would if if certain red lines are
crossed I suppose India may use nuclear
weapons if but I don't think India will
nuke the whole world India will nuke the
aggressor nation and and take it down
too possibly depending on who it is okay
hyphen says does quantum entanglement
mean that the universe is fundamentally
connected
if particles can stay connected is space
really separating anything well quantum
mechanics And
is it a local theory? It's probably not
a local theory.
Um,
if you have quantum entanglement,
it doesn't mean two things are
connected. It means that see if you have
two quantum mechanically entangled
particles, it doesn't mean they're
actually connected. It means that these
two particles are one single system. So
it means that they don't have separate
wave functions. They have the same wave
function. They have a wave function, one
wave function that describes the two
particles. So it's a single system uh
that is interconnected as such. Right?
Quantum mechanically.
But are all particles quantum quantum
mechanically entangled? Not quite.
Right.
So all particles aren't entangled. Some
particles are entangled. You can you can
produce uh entangled particles, pairs of
pairs of particles. You can produce them
through various processes, but it's not
necessary that all the particles in the
world are entangled.
Um
and so let's say you have a pair of
entangled particles that are described
by a single wave function.
Does it mean that possibly space is not
separating them? No, they are
definitely. See that's where quantum
mechanics kind of seems to intersect
with general relativity because when we
talk about space we're talking about
space time
right and the particles are indeed
separated in spaceime
but we're not sure how to describe them
in quantum mechanically in curved space
time but they are indeed in curved
spaceime so there is indeed physical
separation between the particles indeed
if even if they are entangled you can
have one particle in the Andromeda
galaxy and one particle here on the
Earth and they'll still be entangled and
they are still separated by 2 and a half
million light years. Right? So there is
indeed genuine physical and temporal
separation.
And secondly, all particles aren't
quantum mechanically entangled. So the
universe
from that perspective is not entirely
fundamentally connected. Okay.
Vidyman says is Pakistan ever likely to
balconize for internal reasons? it is
very likely to balconize the moment it
stops getting external support from
either the US or China.
Right? So Pakistan will balconize when
India becomes the most powerful entity
in the Indian subcontinent. That's when
Pakistan will balconize.
Which means that India will become more
powerful in the subcontinent than the US
or China. At that point Pakistan will
balconize. But that is far in the future
if it happens ever.
And as long as the Americans or the
Chinese keep supporting Pakistan, it
will not balconize. That's where we are.
So eventually Pakistan will balconize
whenever it happens. Maybe in 5 years,
maybe in 3 years, maybe in 30 years,
eventually it will because it's an
artificial and temporary nation. It's a
fake nation.
Ashish says, "Why do the Jats have such
height of muscular mass and heavy
wrists? How are they were they able to
fight anybody who tried to capture the
land relation to rigid
various parts of India various people
with various uh physical
characteristics.
So I suppose jats are large and more
muscular heavier something to do with
DNA something to do with their genetic
ancestry
but look they are able to fight anybody
who tried to capture the land. Have you
seen the gurkas? Let's say the jats are
6t tall on average. Okay. The gorcas are
56 or 5' seven on average males. Have
you seen the gurkas? Has anybody been
able to capture their land or defeat the
gurkas? So it's not all about muscular
mass and size of risks and size of
whatever. It's not all about that. So
it's it's about it's about tradition and
culture also. The gurkas have this
warrior ethos. They have their own way
of fighting. They have their cookies.
the the what are the two smaller knives
called with the kukri chakmak and
something else. Yeah. So it's not all
about size and muscular mass and wrists
and all that but yeah why are the js
like this? Probably because of whatever
you know genetic history they have.
India is a very very very very diverse
place genetically and yet within that
diversity we diversity we have
uniformity at a relation to rigid we
don't know the juts well there's no
mention of juts in rigid the rigid was
written thousands of years before the
word jat was jat was even imagined by
anyone
um so that comes much later probably
connection with the skitians the
masagate possibly possibly
Prattana says in surveys Hinduism loses
the least numbers. Who does these
surveys? What is the sample size? What's
the methodology of surveys? We have to
ask these questions if we want to
discuss something. Surveys. You can do a
survey with a sample size of 200 people
and then it is known that people
extrapolate that to a nation of 1.4
billion people. People can do surveys of
Indian genetics based on Indian origin
people who live in New York City. Take
50 samples from Indian origin people who
live in New York City and then that
genetic data that you gather, you
extrapolate that to the Indian
subcontinent. Does it work? That's a
very minor small sample size and those
people may have come from only some
parts of the subcontinent. How can you
then project that on the entire
subcontinent?
So these surveys my question is who
first of all is doing these surveys?
Second what is the sample size they have
used? Third how representative is the
sample
of the entire Hinduism.
Fourth what's the methodology of your
survey and so on. Surveys anybody can
throw out a survey here or there you
know. So my point is if these surveys
are correct, I'll be very pleased.
But let us not get complacent because
some surveys say something. Hinduism
may possibly be on its last legs today.
Maybe it won't last five decades. Who
knows? We cannot be complacent.
That's my point.
Shushut says, "How do gravitational
waves help in studying the big bag?"
How do gravitational waves help in
studying the big bang?
They don't really help us directly in
studying the big bang. They help us uh
understand the nature of collisions
between very large gravitational objects
like
let's say two two black holes or two
neutron stars or a neutron star and a
black hole right that's what they help
us understand. So what was the size of
the black hole? What kind of spin
possibly did it have? you know, angular
momentum, um, two black holes, what were
the masses, where did it happen, and so
on. It doesn't really help us studying
the big bang. If you want to study the
big bang, you would need way better
gravitational wave detectors. Let me
explain why. Gravitational waves are
ripples in the fabric of spaceime
itself. Okay, they do exist. We know
that. We know that now. Now we have this
detector called LIGO
laser interferometry
gravitational observatory LIGO. It's a
gigantic detector and it detects
space-time ripples but not ripples. It
detects tsunamis in the fabric of
spaceime waves which are gigantic
huge amplitudes.
So the biggest gravitational wave
amplitudes are detected by LIGO but
they're actually tiny. Now what we want
to detect is not the gravitational wave
tsunamis but the gravitational ripples
in the fabric of space time but LIGO
isn't powerful enough to detect those.
That is what will help us understand the
conditions that were prevalent in the
very early universe right after the big
bang. That's what we need and that's
what we don't have. If we have a
gravitational wave detector that can
actually detect gravitational ripples, I
would personally be very interested in
that. But yeah, so right now we can only
detect tsunamis, not ripples. And that's
why we can understand the parameters of
black hole and uh neutron star
collisions, but not quite the conditions
in the aftermath of the big bang.
ICMBBS says Swiss CHPM concluded that
India achieved all its objectives in May
uh Operation Hindu. Okay. What can India
do better to influence global narratives
that say otherwise? We need to have okay
how can we influence global narratives
that say otherwise? Well, you can do
that by
by purchasing
global publications.
Yeah. By acquiring global publications.
Purchase the New York Times. purchase
the Washington Post, purchase 50
different uh media outlets in the west,
maybe not the prominent ones, but
smaller ones, purchase them and have
them push our propaganda.
That's what you do.
Now, the government should not do it.
Private entities should do it.
So let's say India Indian companies or
whatever purchase 50 different western
media outlets medium-sized ones not very
prominent ones and they all start
pushing Indian propaganda
I am saying propaganda let's push lies
why not push lies why only push the
truth
do that then the narrative changes
another thing India should start doing
playing the same games on social media
that the Chinese and Pakistanis do
whatever tactics they use we should use
those on larger scales. So these are how
this is how you influence global
narratives. You can use a combination of
factors. You use social media plus you
purchase all those media outlets. That
way you control the narrative or at
least a part of the narrative. That's
what you do. But India doesn't play this
game for whatever reason. I just don't
understand what why I don't understand.
Gapati says Buddhism is the precursor to
the Mletcha invasion. Buddhists
supported the Yanas. It was a Buddhist
who betrayed Raja Dahir and sided with
bin Kasim. I don't considered Buddhism
to be a part of Dharma.
I can't disagree with too much you say
except for the last part about
considering Buddhism to be part of
Dharma. It definitely is dharmic path.
So I would disagree with you about that.
But everything else you said I find it
very hard to disagree with.
All right. Harish Sharma says, "I wanted
to start solving game theory, but I was
told it was Epstein's favorite apart
from other things. Should I continue or
will I be a psychopath?" Well, Epstein
was a mathematics teacher as well. Did
you stop learning mathematics?
Was Epstein a mathematics teacher? Let
me see. Okay. Um, Jeffrey, right?
Jeffrey
Epstein mathematics.
Um was he a mathematics teacher?
Um
I think he was in mathematics, right?
Let me see.
Okay. So he he was a physics and
mathematics teacher for teenagers.
So should we stop doing physics and
mathematics?
We should not stop doing it. Right? So
it doesn't matter what Epstein did. He
also breathe oxygen. Should we stop
breathing oxygen?
Okay. So, breathing oxygen won't make
you a psychopath. Doing physics or
mathematics will not make you a
psychopath. All right. Go for it. All
the best.
Okay.
Prattana says I Madras Madras making
Sanskrit AI Tamil chant Riga better but
some politicians want to destroy
Hinduism. How are politicians so
disconnected to people? See it's not
like all politicians are disconnected
with the people. The current
system that we have in India, this
Westminster democracy system,
this federalism in India under the
specific kind of constitution that we
have all of that this all of this this
all these parameters and characteristics
that once they come together they
produce a certain kind of system in
India a political system and this
political system that we have in India
is is not conducive to the long-term
survival of Indian civilization.
So it in this system politicians benefit
from from creating divisions in society.
Politicians benefit from introducing
various forms of chaos in society.
Politicians benefit by being from being
selfish and putting their personal
interests over the national or
civilizational interests. Right? Tamil
Nadalu is a fantastic place. Beautiful
culture, incredibly rich, rich and
ancient culture. Some of the greatest
Hindu sages have come from Tamil Nadu.
Some of the greatest Hindu temples are
in Tamil Nadu. Some of the greatest
emperors we've had are from Tamil Nadu.
From Tamil, the chasers, right? Even
today if you go to Tamil Nadu, the
people are so they are so connected to
our culture. And yet you have other
issues in Tamil Nadu.
The the problem is not Tamil Nadu or
Tamil Nadu's culture. The problem is the
Indian political system.
That's the problem.
Swastik Mahesh says, "What was the flag
of the Kushan Empire?" I'm not sure. Did
the Kushan Empire even have a flag?
Today, every nation must have a flag.
Did we have flags in the past? Did the
Morian Empire have a flag? I'm not sure
we had a flag during the Moran Empire
time. Did the Koshan Empire have a flag?
I'm not sure. We had it. There's there's
no requirement that every empire should
have a flag. Did the Roman Empire have a
flag? They didn't have a flag. Did the
Ottoman Empire have flag? They didn't
have a They did not have a flag. So, I
don't know if the Kushan Empire had a
flag. I don't think they would have had
one. This requirement is a very new
modern requirement. A flag was typically
something you would carry into battle
for protection. You believed that if the
flag had a representation of gods.
So Maharaja Hunjit Singh when he went
into battle he did not carry with him
the flag of the Sikh Empire. He carried
him with him a flag a saffron flag with
a representation of goddess Da on it.
Maharajit Singh of the Sikh Empire. So
flags were typically
some things that invoked divine
protection. That was what flag the
purpose that flags originally served.
Then later in the west it became an ego
thing that you know I have this flag
with three lions on it which means my my
kingdom is is greater or something. That
sort of thing. So I'm not sure the
Kushan Empire even had had a flag.
Shashad Aim says I don't feel very
positive about about our nation anymore.
I would not recommend you to be all
discouraged and all like that.
um we have lasted so long and we will I
think last another thousand years I
yeah this this period of time is such
that yeah it's easy to lose hope
you know we are facing so many problems
we are losing our culture religion all
of that
you have this industrial scale
religious conversion happening in India
there There are lots of issues, lots,
lots of problems
indeed. But I would still say let us be
optimistic. I am optimistic. There are
problems, there are issues. There is the
possibility of vasalization in the next
five years. Five years. Next 5 years is
make or break for India.
But I think eventually we will prevail.
I I personally am still positive over
India. Okay? It'll work out. It will
work out. All right? Be positive. Come
on. Let's be positive. Let's all be
positive together. It will work out.
Fast snail says, "Are FTA's free trade
agreements really good for India or
tariffs needed?" Free trade agreements
are great for India as long as the trade
agreements are balanced and and mutually
beneficial. So, if you have a FTA with
the EU, which is balanced and beneficial
for both sides, that's fantastic.
If you have a FTA with the US that is
balanced and beneficial for both sides,
that's fantastic. But if you have a FTA
with some entity where they get all the
benefits and you get all the pain,
that's not a good FDA, right? So the
quality of an FDA depends on how
beneficial it is for both sides. So for
me, if I have an FDA with a small nation
and I take all the benefits and impose
the most constraints on them, it's
beneficial for me, good for me, but
terrible for the small nation. So
ideally, you want balance. As long as
you have a balanced FTA, it's good for
you.
Uh, diet with precaution says, has
Ukraine become a kamikaza nation for the
west?
Sadly, Ukraine is in deep deep trouble.
It's kind of a disposable tool of asset
of the west right now. You know, I mean,
uh, it's kind of become like that, which
is of course tragic, terrible.
It has kind of become like a disposable
asset for the for the west.
Mango Man says, "I am planning to build
my career
in research domain and wants to p pursue
a PhD in cyber security. Any suggestions
or tips?"
Suggestions or tips? Look, I don't know
at what stage in your
education education you are. Are you in
the 10th00, 12th00 college? Where are
you? Master's degree, where exactly are
you? I don't know. So I don't know what
specific suggestions or tips I can give
you.
Um you want to pursue a PhD in cy cyber
security. What recommendation I would I
would give you is
before you reach the PhD level make sure
you master all the basics and
fundamentals.
If you want to be a researcher you need
to have your basics. You need to be
really strong with your basics. You need
to have mastered your basics. the
fundamentals
the fundamentals of cyber security the
fundamentals of computer science I don't
know data structures algorithms and
whatever it is uh operating systems
and and what what whatever else you have
in cyber security you have to master the
fundamentals if you can do that then you
can do as advanced uh research that you
want yeah so that's that's the advice
I'll give you master the fundamentals.
All the best.
Sagnik Achara says, "Where can our
gallium G chipm capacity go next in 15
years in light of the recent news?"
Which recent news? How can we improve VC
venture capital funding for deep STE
deep tech startups here? Um, GN chipm
What's Gallium G?
um
architecture
generative adversarial network. I'm not
sure if that's what you're asking me
chips. GAN chips. What are GAN chips?
Gallium nitride. Okay. Gallium nitride.
Uh gallium nitride chips. What's it do?
Uh gallium nitride band direct band gap
semiconductor commonly used in blue LEDs
and so on. Um look okay so where can our
gallium nitride chipm
gallium nitrate is a semiconductor I
suppose it has some news in chips I yeah
okay where can it go in the next 10 15
to 15 years in the light of the recent
news which recent news are you talking
about the trade inter trade framework
thing
I don't know if that is relevant to our
uh chipm semic program.
Where can our capabilities,
technological capabilities for
manufacturing chips go in the next 10 to
15 years in the absence of any news? It
will all depend on whether we can
acquire or develop photo lithography
technology.
Photo lithography machines are used to
etch the circuits on chips. Incredibly
detailed circuits on very small chips.
you need auto lithography technology.
The Chinese are trying to reverse
engineer or acquire it somehow using
people who have worked in ASML which is
a Dutch company which which is the uh
world leader in photo lithography
technology. So if India wants to be at
the same level as the US and China in
ship making we will need to master photo
lithography technology. That's what we
need to do and yeah so that's the thing
that's that's the challenge how can we
improve VC funding for deep tech
startups here venture capital funding
well Indian Indian uh venture
capitalists will have to uh well they
will have to change some of their
outlook they will have to develop a
bigger appetite for risk and secondly
think long term don't just cash out once
you once you you know once the company
or or the startup has reached a certain
stage and obviously if the government
can ease ease up the you know improve
the ease of doing business and so on in
India it can certainly help. Yeah.
Namitrana says is if if this path
silenced by Anglo that if we martyed
while saving dharma we will get swa swa
will have sum honey ancestors of saras
dance pleasure and beautiful best things
done thousand times that of earth. It
sounds suspiciously like a very
different religion to me.
Is this path silenced by Anglo?
I'm not exactly sure what you're saying,
but what you are saying is very
suspiciously similar to something a
different religion says. So
uh
Barak Jawan says u removing UGC and
making reservations on economic basis is
vital for Bhat and uh removing cast and
replacing it with Berna and Gautra
system as it used to be. When will we
start to rebuild Bat as it used to be
now when will this happen? I don't know.
I would like this to start right away
tomorrow morning.
Ideally, it should start immediately.
But when will it happen? I it depends on
our leadership, on our elected
leadership. Do they first of all want
this to happen or do they not want it to
happen at all? If they do want it to
happen, then when will they start
working on this? I I don't know.
Um
so I I agree with you. We need to make
reservations
on the basis of family's economic
condition, right? That's what you need
to do instead of doing making on you
know basing it on on cast. We need to
completely remove cast. I completely
agree with you and let people continue
their jati traditions and gutra whatever
right let people do it individually but
there should be no official
cast anywhere on any document. So that's
how we go back to with the way we used
to be.
And uh
so I agree with these things but when do
we start doing this? It's not in our
hands because we don't control the
country. It's the politicians and the
elected people who control the country
and this will happen only when they
decide it's it's it's the time to do it.
I'm not sure when that happens.
It's in their hands.
Uh SDE says Jews roshield play double
games. USA is just a tissue paper. They
are now coming for India to use as
tissue paper Trump is trying hard to
save America so they want them. Okay,
sir. I don't know about this but okay.
Um I haven't studied the history of rose
shields. I don't know about the theories
about Jews controlling the world. I
don't know if they're true or not. Uh so
yeah, don't know.
Honey Sharma says, "Did you ever see a
ghost? Any personal horror story?" I
haven't never seen a ghost.
I've never experienced anything
substantially supernatural.
I've definitely never seen a ghost. So,
I don't have any personal horror
stories. Sorry. Hector Hector Geronimo
says, "Will UFOs be the next scops with
ample evidence evidence? Will any files
be ever released?" Recently, a NASA
scientist said he does believe there are
aliens, but did not talk much about it.
Will UFOs be the next SCOPS? I don't
know what's going to come next. What
SCOP will be next? Um with ample
evidence. Do I know that there is ample
evidence? I don't know about ample
evidence.
I mean if there is evidence that aliens
exist and they're around then why will
only one country see all the evidence.
And why will we not see alien UFOs in
the skies over Delhi in Mumbai? Okay,
Delhi, Mumbai too much pollution but
maybe somewhere else in India. Why won't
why why don't you see UFOs there on a
routine basis like in the US? Why not
over Jakarta?
Why not over you know Tokyo?
Why only in the US? So I don't know if
this is true if there is any evidence
evidence and if they release such
evidence whether that evidence will be
true or will be altered
and somebody said something it makes no
difference to me. I don't care what
people say. Show me the evidence.
Words don't matter. Words are cheap.
Words are words have no meaning or
value. Evidence is what matters. Hard
evidence, not not not ambiguous
evidence. So I don't know if if some
nation suddenly announces that UFOs and
aliens exist, I'll be very suspicious
about it. Actually, I'll be very
skeptical about it. Rajat says, "How are
you?" I'm good. I'm good, sir. Um, thank
you. Recent paper co-authored by Carlo
Roi and Swami Surva Priyananda gives
good perspective on consciousness seen
in seen in Noima magazine. Let's see
uh car loi
swami surand
uh which no a no
magazine let's see what do we have
consciousness across three world views
okay
consciousness across three worldviews
central concepts in three different
domains Hindu tradition In computer
science and quantum physics find
analogies and reflect one another.
Interesting. I I'll not read this whole
thing over here but very interesting and
I shall certainly check this out. I
shall certainly check this out later on
not right now. So thank you so much for
this very interesting recommendation.
Thank you so much indeed Rajat.
And Rajat says, "Will H ever deliver the
Mark 1A again?" Delay news heard. I I
haven't heard this news of the delay.
I'm sure it will delay the Mark 1A, but
what is the cause of the delay? I'm not
sure. And uh I think the government
needs to look into these matters and you
know get on top of these things.
What are the issues? Address the issues.
Yeah. Yeah. We for says Ram Ram g great
efforts as always. Thank you so much Ram
Ramj. Thank you very much indeed. Thank
you. D with Prigoian says want to create
DI Vagner like PMC. Any suggestions?
Uh they vagner like private military
corporation. Any suggestions? First
first suggestion you need to have a
tremendous amount of money.
Second, you need to have access to
prisoner to prisons
where you can recruit certain categories
of prisoners, right? So, you need to
have access, you know, you need to have
permission from the government. You need
to have a lot of money. You need to have
a lot of you need to have people who can
handle those prisoners and turn them
into proper highquality mercenaries. You
need to have people who can give
military training. You need to have
access to arms, ammunition, so many
things. So that's how you and pro
possibly you need to be a chef in the in
the past.
Okay. Rajett says hire talent from
Boeing Safh to build own engine. We can
do that. Yeah sure why not? But for that
you need money. And not just the talent
you need to pour in at least a billion
dollars into the program. You can
certainly hire talent that will require
money like good good amounts of money.
But then you will need to source all the
hardware do all the testing. You need a
wind tunnel. You need u an aircraft on
which you can test the engine. Then you
need to build multiple iterations of the
engine. Some of these will not work.
Some will work better. Some will blow
up. You need a lot of money to do this.
India doesn't invest money in these
matters. So
what can I say? Sueda says, "What are
your thoughts on causality and unarity?
Is it safe to say we both can't that
both can't be true simultaneously unless
you use the multiple worlds
interpretation?" The many worlds
interpretation. I personally think
unitarity is map and not territory. It's
possible unit territory is map and not
territory. Map. Yeah. What's my thoughts
on causality and unit? I think also I
tend to believe that union territory is
more map and less the territory right um
is it safe to say that both can't be
true simultaneously
unless you use the many worlds
interpretation
what does the many worlds interpretation
say about
unitarity
uh both can't be true
so the universe can't be causal and
unitary at the same time unless you use
the many worlds interpretation.
I'm not entirely sure right now
uh the Everettian multi manual worlds
interpretation.
I I I what I can say is that I kind of
agree with you that unitarity is more
the map more likely to be map and not
territory. Not sure whether what the
many words interpretation would say
about this.
Yeah. So that's what I can say at this
point. Yeah, unitarity is most most
likely map and not territory.
Seda again the same question. Okay, you
have the same question repeated. Well,
anyway, yeah. OCI holder says,
EU passport for growth or stay Indian.
Your opinion, it's entirely your choice.
Entirely your choice.
I will say you decide for yourself what
what you think is best for yourself.
Yeah.
Ask yourself this question. Will you be
able to get the growth you want,
desire or deserve if you stay Indian?
If you will stay Indian, if you won't
get the growth you want in India, then
ask yourself that is your love for the
country more important than personal
growth. If that's the case, you stay
Indian. Otherwise, you go for a EU
passport. So, you have decided yourself,
sir. Okay. Right. Iraq says, "We have uh
majestic temples in India. We are aware
of their patron dynasties, but I would
like to know about the engineers. Who
are they?" We have no idea. We've lost
all the information. We've lost all the
information about the engineers, right?
We don't have any records left.
Sometimes in some temples, you may have
some inscription with some names, but
some could be donors, some could be
patrons, engineers, I'm not sure. So, we
have lost the information. All the
records have been destroyed.
Uh so yeah
says for centuries pre-Jewish Israel at
local kings with mitani influenced arian
names like akaps indro
ashkalon shubandu megidos beridya etc
and elite military aristocracy called
Maranu.
Okay, let me check out some of these
names.
Accepts
Indro.
What is that? Uh, Indro
or is it a
with a apostrophe? Is it
I'm not sure about that. Okay, let's
see. Ashkillons. Okay.
Okay, let's just go with Androda. Who is
Ah
who is Indro? A st a sage a son etc etc
etc. Okay subhandu
subandu. What is that? Subandu.
Ashkalon. Right.
Ashkalon.
There is no direct connection. Okay. So
I'm not sure but all right.
So I'm not aware of this and I'm not
able to find immediate information about
this. I'm sure it's there but I'll have
to dig a little deeper into it. So I'll
check it out sir. Thank you very much
for the
interesting fact oid.
Oh yeah. Thank you. Uh Rohani says do
you take notes while reading to retain
info better?
No.
I will sometimes underline stuff but I
don't take notes while reading. Um I'm
sure I would have done some kind of for
for some form of note takingaking when I
was still a student back in the day.
I would have reinterpreted what I read
in my own own words to make it easier
easier for me to retain it. I would have
done that back in the day. But today
when I read I don't take notes. Today
when I read I will sometimes underline
stuff but uh I don't take notes anymore.
The national the rational reporter says
has philosophy interested you? Do you
what do you want India to produce the
most great philosophers, mathematicians,
physicists or economics? Economists and
in what what order? Philosophy
fascinates me but I've never had the
time to study it in any great detail.
It's fascinating for sure. Uh yeah. So
what do I want India to produce the
most? Great philosophers,
mathematicians, economists,
physicists and in what order?
Um what does India need the most?
Engineers,
physicists,
mathematicians, sure.
India needs engineers the most
also physicists.
Economists maybe in a small small
number. What do economists produce? We
know what engineers produce. They
produce real world things. What do
physicists produce? They they produce
advances in physics that can be used in
in the real world by engineers. What do
mathematicians produce? They produce new
techniques and new concepts. But
techniques that can be used in physics
that can be used by engineers. So yes,
we need engineers in large numbers,
physicists in reasonable numbers,
mathematicians in small numbers,
economists in smaller numbers,
philosophers in whatever number they
would want to produce themselves.
philosophers well they don't actually
produce any real world goods but they
are of course important so yeah
died with prejun says can we can India
have a brahmos like joint venture for
jet engine gas turbines with npo satyan
or kuznatsov three Chinese killed in
Tajik border clash with any raw
involvement I am not aware of this tajik
border clash I'm not seen that can India
have brahosl like joint venture for jet
engine gas turbines with npo satin or
khnets of Russian companies, Russian um
jet engine manufacturers. Can we have
it? I suppose we could have it. It would
we be for both governments to come to
the right terms for a joint venture.
It's certainly possible
provided both governments are willing
and they can come they can arrive at a
at at at a good kind of understanding
and agreement. It's possible.
Pratep Kumar Roy has become a new
member. Thank you so much Pratib Kumar
Roy G. I really appreciate it and
welcome to the membership of this
channel. Thank you sir.
Ply no pycraft AI central says after 40
years of long growth India's market cap
overtook Hong Kong and several EU
markets. Why do global financial media
like Bloomberg still give more focus to
EU and in Hong Kong?
Because they don't they're not pleased
with the fact that India is over
overtaking these western or western
controlled economies. Hong Kong used to
be a western control economy and right
now it's a Chinese economy, right? Um
but India is a nation that was formerly
defeated. It's a culture, it's a
civilization that was formerly defeated
and it's now standing back up on its
feet and it's kind of rising and they
they can't stand it.
So they will always underplay India's
achievements.
Now slowly India's achievements are
becoming almost too large and too
significant to ignore.
But they'll still try and do that. It's
it's the it's indophobia. Let's call it
that. Okay.
Okay. Mama bucket VFX says, "Please
check out Bashar Prime Radiant ET
entity." Bashar Prime Radiant. Let's
see.
Prime radiant. What is that? the prime
radiant understanding uh the god
particle
all of existence is made from the same
um
okay there's a there's a there's a
article over here and it's about what
let me check it out the prime radiant
understanding the god particle the
universe is vast
particle every action thought and
particle plays a crucial at the heart of
the prime radiant a profound concept
this blog post will embark on the
explanation. Okay. Okay. Okay. I will I
will check it out. I'll not read the
whole thing right now because we are
doing a Q&A. But thank you once again
for that recommendation indeed.
Um
drive with precaution says rupee value
has been dropping continuously since
1947. What's my opinion?
Yeah, it's been dropping. It's it's just
a fact of life. That's that's the thing.
In the past, the rupee was not a free
floating currency. It was uh controlled
tightly by the government of India and
it's it's been devalued multiple times o
over the years over the decades.
Eventually after 1991 or '92 it became a
free floating currency and then it's uh
then it's been manipulated by by market
forces and maybe something more than
market forces, right? Um
so it's just a fact of life. It is what
it is. Um
and right now it's still kind of
dropping compared to the value of the
dollar. The dollar obviously is is this
artificially propped up currency. So
we'll see about that in the long run.
Vihung Kuran says thank you Aijit sir
for your guidance answering our
questions and raising our standards
through these live streams. I really
enjoy them. Thank you so much sir. Thank
you to you Vhung and thank you to all of
our viewers for all the very interesting
questions that you ask me. I try my best
to answer of of course sometimes I may
not be able to answer but I try my best.
So thank you all of you as well for
making this channel what it is right
it's because of these interactions that
this that that we have this community
that we have right now and we discuss so
many interesting things. So thank you to
all of you all my viewers past and
present and future. Thank you. Victor
Geronimos says, "Will UFOs be
I took this question. How come it's
repeated? I took this question a while
ago." So, uh, Godliness says, "I know
nothing will happen, but I will still
try. Can someone please for God's sake
implement traffic rules on the Indian
streets and highways? Driving is now
becoming life-threatening."
What can I say? What can I say?
There's no enforcement of traffic rules
in India, right? I mean in some parts of
some cities you may have some
enforcement but overall in India it's
you know you leave it to the gods
unfortunately. Vir Kamat says reports
claim that serum AI has outperformed
Gemini in latest benchmarks. Can you
analyze? Uh analysis I can't do right
now live but let's see what server AI
is. I've heard about it. I'm hearing
good things about serum AI.
What is Serum AI? Sovereign Indian AI
ecosystem for LLM's agents and whatn
not. So what does Wikip have to say
about this? AI is focusing these large
consumers for Indian languages and
context building efficient Indian
language voice bots and all of that uh
technology funding founding etc
reception serum agent servant serum 2B
uh shuka 1.0 audio long language model
server models A1 and so on. Okay, it
doesn't say much here. What? Let's see
what server uh has to say on uh Twitter.
Will it ever open up? So,
do we have anything about the latest uh
benchmarks?
Uh meet blah blah blah serum 2B.
Let's see.
So, serum M
24 billion open weights hybrid model
general knowledge.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. It's doing
pretty well actually. It's doing pretty
well. Okay. So, I I will not go through
all of this right now, but uh looks very
interesting. And if this is genuinely a
sovereign AI, fantastic. I will have to
check it out and take it for a test test
drive, I would say.
Godliness says, "We want a podcast on
alien life and space mystery." You want
a podcast or do you want a live stream?
Podcast. Well, somebody will have to
host me for that. And people want to
host me for history and geopolitics, but
never science.
Uh, alien life and space mysteries. We
could discuss that.
If it's a live stream you want, I could
do a live stream in which I take your
questions. If it's a podcast, we'll see
about that. But anyway, I'm glad
somebody's interested in this stuff.
Yeah.
SK1 sk1sk says, "Okay, nothing." Thank
you. Thank you so much. Thank you very
much. Uh Sam the gamer says if our moon
was tidily unlocked like Hyperion, well
it would be a different uh experience we
would have here on the planet. Um the
moon is tidly tidly locked in what what
resonance? Some resonance resonance with
the earth which is why see the moon's
rotation period is the same as the time
it takes for it to go around the earth
once. So it rotates. It also goes around
the earth. Revolution orbits the earth.
So one
rotation of the moon is the same as the
time it takes to orbit the earth once.
Which is why we only see one face of the
moon. If it was not tidily locked, would
it be more chaotic for the planet Earth?
It would be different and not
necessarily more chaotic. Yeah.
the moon would not be at the same
distance as it is with us right now. In
that case, it would not be tidily locked
and yeah, even if it's a different
distance, the the the it can still be
tid tidily locked with a different
period of rotation. But if it was tidily
unlocked,
we would have a different experience
here on Earth of the moon, I suppose.
A Matt Blackbeard says, "Why hasn't
India reverse engineered the Sukoy30s
AL31 FP or Mirage Mirage's M53 engines?
Why not a dual cavary jet or Russian
powered indigenous airframe?"
Well, I don't know why India has not
bothered to reverse engineer anything.
When the Russians sold various system
systems to the Chinese, the Chinese
reverse engineered everything. The
Chinese have their own indigenous jet
engine now which is obviously a reverse
engineered Russian engine.
The Chinese do this. India never does a
thing because India has no ambition I
suppose
because the Indian um model for military
procurement was always import stuff
never try to become self-sufficient.
It obviously points to a lack of
ambition or a lack of leadership
qualities somewhere along the way where
I don't know whether it's the very top
or at various levels in the military I'm
not sure I would say I would put the
blame not in the military itself
definitely some blame has to be shared
by the military but I think above the
military
that's why we have never reverse
engineered anything I mean the Chinese
took the the MIG 21 and developed it
into the JF7
right which is a decent aircraft we
didn't even bother to do that
so India lacks ambition right even today
we could reverse engineer various things
but we don't seem to be doing it
um
godliness says what's my forecast on the
upcoming Bangladeshi elections I think
my forecast I have no idea about the
Bangladeshi polit politics I don't care
my forecast is that whatever the
Americans want will happen that's my
forecast I think that's a pretty
accurate
and clear forecast. Whatever the
Americans want will happen in Bangladesh
in the upcoming Bangladesh elections.
Okay. Jura TV says, "Is it possible for
the US Navy and intelligence to track
info of each and every shallow fleet
tanker in the ocean or is it a difficult
task?" It is 100% possible for the US
Navy and intelligence to track the info
of each and every of these shadow fleet
tankers. They have this vast network of
satellites. They know everything that's
happening in real time. It's difficult.
But if you have 10,000 satellites in
space, very possible. And now you have
tens of thousands of starling satellites
which may have other capabilities also.
So the Americans can monitor everything,
track everything in real time.
Pratik Shenoi says, "How accurate are
modern portrayals of pre-Christian Greek
and Norse societies as morally corrupt,
univilized, brutal? To what extent is
this view shaped by movies and TV rather
than history?" Much love to you. Thank
you so much. Uh modern portrayals of
pre-Christian Greek and north nor
societies morally all that.
Well, these modern portrayals are indeed
very much strongly very strongly
influenced by Christianity.
Christianity sees
polytheism as evil, as demonic, as
satanic, right?
So, I mean, uh, if you watch that series
called Vikings,
they portray Viking culture as pretty
weird. I mean bloodthirsty and
I'm sure pretty inaccurately right.
Um
so a lot of this view the view is not
shaped by movies and TV it's shaped by
Christianity. Christianity has always
portrayed polytheistic cultures as evil
and backward and all that. So the view
is shaped by Christianity not by TV TV
or movies.
Okay. Mary Kane, Mary Kane, ma'am, good
to see you always. I'm noticing next
level auto comment bots in your Q&As and
collabs with others. CIB coordinated
inauthentic behavior that bypass
platform security trying to create
account karma.
Well, um, thank you for pointing this
out. I
I'm I'm sure I've noticed some of it. Uh
I've not seen the comments in my collabs
with others because there are so many of
those these days. Uh but okay, it's
interesting that this is happening. I'll
try and check it out. Um okay. So, thank
you. Thank you so much, Mary. Thank Mary
G for pointing this out and thank you as
always for being such a great supporter.
Thank you so much, Mary.
Dark Side of the Moon says, "Listen,
publications." Not at this time. Not
over here. I'll I'll show you one. I'll
show you one. Okay,
this one. Dark matter
and stable
bound states of primordial black holes.
So, if you go to this here,
uh there is this journal called Okay,
I'm human. Thank you. I am indeed. Okay,
I've got to do stuff now. Prick all
creatures that could shelter in the
item. I got to pick some birds, I
suppose. One, two, three. Three birds
and now we've got to submit this.
Come on IOP science. So this is a
journal called classical and quantum
gravity. Can I please not do all this?
Yeah. And this is a research paper from
May 20, 2002.
Dark matter and stable primordial stable
bound states of primordial black holes.
is published in the journal of classical
and quantum gravity
and it's about dark matter and prim and
primordial black holes. So that's one
and you can look up whatever else is
there. Thank you. Okay. Dial with prejud
says why was popart?
What's popart?
What's
nine? Okay. I I don't know what popart
is. I it's clearly a euphemism for
somebody but I'm not sure what popat is.
So
okay reintor says does India have more
than enough rare earth metals so in
future when China tries to limit it
should it there shouldn't be any
problems but it also it's very important
for atma and various sectors. India has
the world's largest reserves of rare
earths rare earth elements including
metals. India I repeat has the world's
largest reserves of rare earth elements
but India has never bothered to develop
the capacity
to extract
refine and purify these rare earths into
what you use industrially and
commercially.
We don't do the mining. We don't do the
refining on the purification. We don't
do any of that. The Chinese do it. So,
we have everything, but we don't have
the capacity
to
actually use it. That's the problem. But
it's there. That's why the Americans
want India intact silica, right? So if
we start developing the ability to
extract, mine, extract, refine the rare
earths and produce the finished goods,
it may take us 5 to 10 years at least.
Once we do that, we will no longer be
dependent on any anybody else,
especially the Chinese.
Mr. Draula is Draula. Yes. Mr. Draula
says, don't you think that CCP is
pushing itself? Don't you think that CCP
is pushing itself as a new party that
India needs a new party? We can make
sure it remains a regional power just by
pointing out I'm not sure what you're
asking sir.
Chinese Communist Party is pushing
itself as a new party that India needs a
new party so it can make sure it remains
a regional power
just by pointing out flaws. I'm not
really sure what you're asking sir. I
really I'm really sorry I'm not able to
get understand what is what what what
you are trying to ask. I'm not sure.
I'm not sure. I'm very sorry.
Arismanticoro manticor says the elites
ruling the west are absolute Fabian
socialists. The words spoken by the
leaders in the past are extremely
disgusting. It's a blight upon this
world and creates people like Epstein.
I'm not sure about Fabian socialism.
The elites who rule the west are
capitalists.
They are acceleration accelerationists.
They are not Fabian socialists. Fabian
socialism was all about making change
very slowly, very gradual change. The
Nairovian rate of growth that was Fabian
socialism in action. Um so the elites
ruling the west are capitalists. They
are accelerationists.
They want things to go faster. They want
change to happen faster. They want
control over the world. Uh the words
spoken by the leaders in the past are
extremely disgusting. I suppose they
could be. Um and it creates people like
like very sad and pretty ghastly that
something like this happens. But yeah,
we have it. It's all over the place.
They were all involved in this. And
look, Epstein is dead allegedly.
Apparently, his Fortnite account is
still active.
So, that's interesting. But, okay, let's
say he's dead. Do you think there's no
other Epstein out there in the world?
Hard to hard to imagine that, sir. Uh,
the Chimpllo guy, the Chimplok guy says,
"Your thoughts on making India. Was it
successful? Was it failure?" Yeah, the
data is confusing from FDI and other
sources. I think it's not a failure but
it's not a success either. It's
somewhere in between.
Making India hasn't succeeded to the
extent that we would have wanted it to
succeed. I mean, what does India
manufacture and produce for the world
right now? Not a lot, right? But there
is there are some positive stories and
positive outcomes that have emerged from
making India.
For example, much of the success that we
saw in operation sindur was because of
atmunda because of made in India
military equipment, right? I mean we
today we can say with confidence that we
have the world's best battle tested air
defense system indigenous. So there are
successes
in certain sectors but it's not
successful the to the extent that we
wanted would we would have wanted it to
be over the past one decade right more
than one decade we haven't become a
major manufacturing power that is uh
definitely not successful so we are
somewhere in between I think there is
still a lot of potential in making India
but it's not a failure as such it's not
neither a success somewhere in
Inferno Jesus, whenever mainstream media
makes noise,
is it prudent to look elsewhere to see
what they're trying to hide? For
example, Trump tariffs and Maduro's
kidnap. I would say right now the
biggest noise on mainstream media
probably is the Epstein files.
So if the Epstein files are happening
and there's all this noise about it,
what are they trying to hide
potentially? Yeah. So, it's always
prudent
to be cautious and to be skeptical when
there's a big amount of noise being made
about something. Always ask yourself,
are they trying to divert everyone's
attention away from something else
that's more important? It is prudent to
do this. It's a good approach to have.
It's a approach that reveals a certain
extent of critical thinking in your
head. Right? So, yes, do look elsewhere.
Try and look around and see what else.
What are the shadow signals you're
seeing?
What's obviously you can't suppress
everything but you try and keep it
hidden suppressed.
So yeah, it's a good approach to have.
Pratib Kumar Roy says black guard sorry
what did I say? Black guard. Okay, I
think my mind is now scrambled after
almost four hours of this. Black Rock,
Vanguard, and State Street collectively
manage over $30 trillion in assets. 88%
of CEOs of the SNP 500 are controlled by
them. Financial industrial complex is
actually stronger than the defense
industrial complex. I cannot disagree
with you. I agree with you. So, I'm not
sure if the $30 trillion uh amount is
correct or not, but I'm sure it is. You
must have done your research. Um, Black
Rockck, Vanguard, States. Okay. State
Street, I'm not sure, but Black Rock and
Vanguard I'm aware of. They do collect
tremen do collectively manage a very
very large number
quantum of assets. Yes.
So yeah the financial industry complex
obviously it's actually stronger and uh
yeah than the defense industry complex.
I agree. Vir Kamat says best way
Indian-Americans can be agents of
Dharmic civilization.
How can Indian-Americans be agents of
Dharmic civilization?
Um, first of all, um,
do we even have a Dharmic civilization?
But, okay, let's say India is the
Dharmic civilization. How can
Indian-Americans be agents of Dharmic
civilization? Well, first of all, if you
are American citizens, it is your dharma
not to betray your country. So you you
have to obviously uh be loyal to your
country but you can also be
uh you could say uh ambassadors of
Dharmic civilization and Dharma. How to
do that? Well, what Indian Americans
should do is they should organize and
uni and and unite instead of being you
know this divided set of people.
Indian-Americans don't learn from the
Jewish Americans. See how they are
always united and cohesive in their
actions.
They of course are American citizens but
they also promote Jewish interests and
Israeli interests. Learn from them
whatever they are super successful
aren't they at everything. Indians are
also super successful individually in an
individual capacity but they don't
they're not they're spectacularly
spectacular failures at a group level
unlike the Israeli or or or Jewish
Americans. So learn from the Jewish
Americans,
right? Unite instead of fighting amongst
each other all the time. Unite and then
you can be better agents of Dharma.
Pratik Pratipkumar roices I'm a Bengali
Brahman. We've had this goat bala in
front of our Kul Dvi every year which
have recently been stopped due to some
government order. I don't know whether
it's the right thing to do. Why worship
even
the government should never come and
interfere in private religious matters.
I mean I can think of another religious
practice where goats are sacrificed in
very large numbers.
So why has this been stopped for Bengali
Brahmans?
That is terrible. I'm so sorry to hear
this.
I am so sorry to hear this. I don't know
what to do. I I don't know what to tell
you. What you should do. I don't
understand why this would happen. The
the government has no right to interfere
in private religious practices.
Right.
Terrible. I I hope this this is
reversed. Maybe you should go to the
court to the judiciary. I don't know.
Terrible. Like I keep saying, India is a
India is a Hindu phobic, apathide state.
This is terrible. I'm sorry to hear
this, sir.
Somi Shankr, thank you very much. Somi
Shankar G, thank you.
YT user 786 says, "Why do you think
original Gorkcas are not joining Gorka
regiment of Indian army? Instead prefer
British, Singapore or Burmese army?"
Burmese really last couple of years no
Gorcas joining Indian army. Um there
could be multiple reasons. First of all,
why do the Gurkas prefer the British
army or Singapore army? better pay
much more pay right you get a lot more
money if you are serving in the British
army or maybe the Singapore army Burmese
army I'm not sure about that last couple
of years no gurkas joining Indian army
maybe there are political reasons for
that the Nepalese politicians are all
pro-China and anti-India most of them at
least you know the main majority of them
so maybe there's there's a political
reason for reason for that for Gulkas
not joining the Indian army now the last
couple of Yes. Does it have something to
do with the Agnes keep? I am not sure
about that. But definitely political
reasons. Um so the Indian army can't pay
as much as the British army, right? So
that's another reason for for the other
phenomenon of them preferring the
British army. But then you're serving
the the original oppressors, aren't you?
But it is what it is. You know, people
have to make their own decisions based
on uh personal needs and requirements.
So I think that that's the situation.
Uh Sam the Gamer says India's 2015
facile material stock 1 to2K 300 nukes
uh there I don't have the studies right
now in front of me but there there are
these studies that were taken that were
done in the 2010s maybe around 2015 to
17 or 18
uh trying to estimate how much file
material does India actually have and if
you tally that up together based on you
know
reasonably accurate estimates then it
was found that India has sufficient file
material for at least 2,000 nuclear
warheads
at least 2,000
and it it includes file material that's
used in nuclear reactors and whatn not
but India has enough file material for
at least 2,000 nuclear warheads
so yeah how many do we I've actually
I I I couldn't possibly guess. I don't
know.
Okay. Humanity survive says, "I enjoy
working out when you're alive." Well, do
enjoy your workouts. I'm glad that I
contribute to to your enjoyment of your
workouts. Working out is
is fantastic. It's essential for a
healthy life. So, I'm glad I I'm glad to
be of service. Do keep on doing your
workouts. Enjoy them. Thank you.
Slendy's says, "How is demographic
change occurring? How can we counter?
How are they able to behave so organized
and like a hive mind? How can Hindus do
it too?"
Look, I will not go into the religious
matters here. How is demographic change
happening? One way of this is uh through
illegal immigration.
We apparently have very open and porous
borders between India and Bangladesh,
East Pakistan. and Bangladeshes have
been pouring into India for decades and
the government of India has somehow
failed to stop this.
So in the year 2016 uh Shri Kiran Riuji
GI had said in parliament that there are
probably around
2 cr Bangladeshes in India in 2016 20
million today is 2026 a it's been a
decade how many do we have today that's
the question definitely way more than 20
million now so that's one way of doing
demographic change by p pushing in
Bangladeshes in tremendous numbers into
India and they will not come and sit in
India they'll multiply
they will have children born here in
large large large numbers what about the
Rohhingas you have Rohingya all over
India in Jammu you have Rohingya
settlements in Jammu
then apparently during the operation
Sundur India discovered tens of
thousands of Pakistanis who have been
living in India for decades then you
have the Manipur disaster which is
unfolding in front of our eyes right now
cookie land for Christ lacks apparently
of cookies Burmese people who
crossed over into India and who are
squatting on Manipur territory.
This is how demographic change happens.
This is one way of demographic change
happening. Another way is through
industrial scale demographic
re-engineering through religious
conversions that's happening in various
states of India. How can we counter the
government should end these practices?
The government should uh detect and
deport all the illegal infiltrators
whether they are Bangladesh, Rohingya,
Pakistanis, cookies, whatever.
Everyone who has come to India illegally
should be deported. Second, stop these
industrial scale religious conversions.
I have no issue with someone deciding
deciding on his or her own that they
want to worship a certain god or convert
to a certain religion. It's a private
matter. It's a personal choice. I will
never oppose any individual's
choice to convert to whatever religion
you want to convert to religion X or Y
or Z, that's entirely your choice. But
it has to come from inside you. It
should not be shoved upon you top down
the way these industrial scale
conversions are happening. That is
demographic re-engineering. That's not
personal choice. So the government
should do something about this. Why is
the government allowing this to happen?
So there are so many ways of countering
this but it doesn't look like we have
any political will to do do that right
now.
Anand Gribbal says, "How to find equal
power for men which doesn't care for
pain and I see so much wrong going
misused power and can elite
culture end because of how many
questions do we have? How to find equal
power for men which doesn't care for
pain? What does that even mean?" And I
see so much wrong going misused power
and can elite culture end because of
epist file. Okay, I'm not able to
understand the first couple questions
but I'll try and address the last one.
Can
elite culture end because of Epstein
files? You mean this ghastly culture
that the Americans in the West have of
the PDF file thing and the the what they
do to children and babies and whatnot,
will that end because it's been revealed
in the Epstein files, the trafficking of
underage human beings and all that. Will
it end because of the Epstein files? No,
it won't end. Still going on. Sadly,
it won't end because of the Epson files.
The epinion files are about
it's about exposing the old elite.
It's about
it's about the power the the powers that
be exposing the old elite and making
them irrelevant.
But there's new elite who I don't know
maybe they continue this nonsense this
atrocious horrific behavior. Maybe they
do. So I don't think the Epstein files
will end this culture. I think the
culture will continue and uh
I don't know what the cure to that is.
So Kumar Roy says wrong treatments organ
trafficking bodies alive or dead not
just skeletons 1980s Kolkata was much
more sanitized history maloc active
through hospitals none of us are safe it
seems
yeah 1980s Kolkata well so I' I I've
only heard about this skeleton thing the
sale of these skeletons I don't know
that there was like millions of them
which sounds I mean which indicates
something really really really wrong.
Something really horrific that happened.
I don't know who did this and why was no
no one ever punished but looks like
there was so much more to this. Yeah,
maybe somebody needs to investigate this
in detail. Maybe the government of India
needs to wake up and look into this
because if those people weren't
punished,
they can still do that.
Yeah.
Okay. Gora TV says, "I don't see any
point of propaganda wars. overwhelming
strike delivers visible results that
don't require propaganda like 1971
results.
There is a lot of value to propaganda
wars.
You can win without fighting.
You can demoralize the enemy without
having to land a single punch, a single
blow, a single $2 million missile.
There's a tremendous amount of value to
propaganda.
It will deliver invisible results
that the victims themselves won't see.
Okay, these are the dark arts of
geopolitics. There's a tremendous amount
of value in that.
Ankumar says, "What was the pre-European
dharmic equivalent of a PhD?" Nobody had
PhDs. Nobody cared about PhDs.
What was the
dharmic? See it was being regarded as a
guru.
Today Indians imagine that a guru your
teachers are your gurus. Yeah. You stop
paying your teachers they won't give you
give you one more second of of you know
knowledge.
The moment you stop paying your fees you
think your teachers will teach you.
They'll ask you to leave. Did a guru
ever do that? So to be regarded as a
guru you had to be the wisest of the
wise the most knowledgeable of the of
the knowledgeable. So being regarded as
a guru was the true I mean today any any
Tom Dick or Harry can get a PhD. Okay if
you look at the the standards of the
Indian PhD thesis it's it's absolute
garbage. Go to show Ganga let me show
you okay I mean the let's do this
show the Ganga reservoir of Indian
thesis.
Okay. Uh search thesis on in to show the
Ganga. Uh what shall we search for? Uh
let's say sociology.
Let us see. Sociology thesis
imprisonment and women. A sociological
study. Sociology of teacher student
relation. Let's okay. Let's not do that.
Uh impact on duran
a sociological analysis.
Okay, stop that. Whoever this person is,
I don't, it doesn't matter. When was
this done? 2005.
Uh, content chapter one.
Uh, okay. It's asking me to download the
stuff. My My point is, my point is the
Indian PhD thesis is trash. The average
Indian PhD. Um, I think the pre-European
dharmic equivalent was guru.
Anand Anad Gribbal says so much lack of
trust among people in how to create mess
which is ruining Janzi and millennial
and future scares me because they don't
understand things. So we can fix this by
fixing the education system and we will
we will once again have tremendously
highquality individuals.
Maybe the genzies and millennials and
genpha are you know they don't
understand things. It's not their fault
the system has done this to them. Let's
let's make sure generation beta, gen B,
gen beta is much better quality by
reforming the education system.
So it can be done. All these problems
can be fixed if there is
the right leadership and the will to do
this.
Aris Manticor says the Epstein files
have invoked a new wave. Anti-semitism
is on an inexplicable rise along with
anti-feminism, anti-trans and anti-
vocism. A roachchild
lost a court case in the US according to
who?
I'm not aware of any of these things.
There's a new wave of anti-semitism,
anti-feminism, anti-rans, antivism.
Are these all connected to the Epstein
files? I'm not sure if it's connected to
the Epstein files. Roachchild lost a
court case in the US. I'm not aware of
that also. So look, I am not aware of
these things. I have to look it up and
then perhaps see if there's a connection
to the Epstein files. And is there a
warning to someone? I don't know. So
okay, Abhir Sarcar says, "Is it wise to
trust people in real life in order to
build connections knowing how often
history shows betrayal and
self-interest?"
It is highly unwise to trust people in
real life.
Unless they are your family. Even in
family you have to be careful. Look in
your life. Let's say you live 80. Let's
say you live 100 years. You're going to
have in your entire life maybe three to
five persons you can genuinely trust.
You're going to meet hundreds of people
in your entire life. You may have if you
are lucky you will have three to five
people who you can trust completely.
Okay. But you have to build connections
in life. So you build those connections
but you have to be careful. You can't
trust anybody entirely and completely.
You have to be careful. You have to be
prudent. So don't trust people blindly.
Uh McLevin says what are the options for
general category people now? Vote for
opposition or not? You vote for the
opposition you're going to go from the
frying pan into the fire. Okay.
Right now you're in the frying pan.
Frying pan. You vote for not or
opposition. You're going to jump into
the fire itself. What are the options? I
don't know what are the options. What
are the options?
I don't know what are the options.
Yeah.
Trust in God
and vote for the leader, I suppose. I
don't know. Uh YT user says, "Should
India adopt Chinese way of reverse
engineering?" Give me a second. Uh
okay. Should India adopt the Chinese way
of reverse engineering and stealing
technology from the west to to fasttrack
advancement instead of reinventing the
wheel? Indians working abroad don't have
nationalistic goals. Should India
reverse engineer things? India should
reverse engineer everything possible.
Everyone does it. Even the west has done
that. Even the west has stolen
technology and knowledge and whatnot.
They constantly
steal Indian ancient knowledge and you
know claim that it's all their
invention.
There there's nothing ethical about what
they do. So India should go ahead and
reverse engineer everything that's
possible. Absolutely everything
possible. Yeah. Uh mantor says Siri no
is an Indian startup to build electric
batterybased jet engines. Electric
battery based jet engines it's usually
under the radar but it has done
incredible work. Unfortunately the Brits
have brought the bought the company
another missed opportunity is its sinor.
Let's see what is serenor
sustainable aviation
zero true zero emission jet turbines
electric jet engines
Norwegian startup how did it become
Norwegian you're saying it's Indian
uh sirino technology private
manufacturing machine it looks like
there are two different companies one is
the sirino Indian thing
and
serial technologies rise of a valuation.
Okay. I I'll have to look into this.
I'll not do the research right now, but
looks like it's what you're saying is
probably true. Yeah, I'll look into it.
Thank you. Okay. Anul says, "Yad's
surname has ancient roots. If the Yadavs
were a warrior clan, how did strong
vegetarian traditions emerge later?" I
am not aware of the
history of the Yadav clan. I haven't
studied it. So I don't know when did
these vegetarian traditions emerge? Are
all Yadavs vegetarian? Has the Yadav
clan had this long-standing tradition of
vegetarianism?
Clearly they were warriors initially
back in the days of Sushi Krishna. So I
don't know when what happened so can't
really say.
OCI holder says game theory says choose
EU passport says India I'll give you a
solution
choose the EU passport
have an OCI card work in the EU amass
money amass experience amass
uh skills
become a person of substance become a
billionaire then you can
invest in India
You see it works both ways. It's a
win-win situation then. But this the
condition is that you have to become
either a millionaire, multimillionaire
or billionaire. So make it happen sir.
Make it happen. Ankita Kachab says I
hope we get the opportunity to read your
published book or books in 2026. I shall
make it happen. Thank you so much Madam
Ankita G for reminding me of this. I
need these reminders so that I don't uh
get complacent. Thank you so much ma'am
for the reminder. Shreas Mitra says
thank you for doing these sessions. I am
learning so much from these sessions.
Heartfelt gratitude to you and for the
other members and to the other members
who ask amazing questions. Thank you so
much Shas to you and to all the members
and to everybody who ask questions. My
only
issue is that I can't answer everybody's
questions because I simply can't. But
thank you so much everybody indeed very
much.
Slendy's says your thoughts on
ddollarization future of future of India
TN
what's India TN thoughts on dorization I
think eventually it'll happen right it
will all depend on how powerful or not
the US is
as long as the US remains the all
powerful entity
the dollar will remain super relevant
unless India Russia China get together
and do something about it along with
breaks
So it's still you know
it's not decided yet whether this will
happen but yeah the dollar is getting
weaker and one way of the US getting rid
of its debt is maybe de you know slowly
deflating the value of the dollar that's
another thing they could do so we'll see
Shashu Zizu Shashu Zizu says is the
global south the swing vote in
geopolitics
there's no voting in geopolitics It's
not a democracy. You see the the the
global order isn't democratic.
It it works on the principle of the rule
of the jungle. Might is right. So the
global south isn't a swing vote. It has
no vote. Only the powerful have a vote
or a say.
Okay. Hyphen says one more super chat
just so that this stream lasts a little
few seconds longer. Blockbuster live
stream as always. Thank you so much. But
thank you very much. Uh it's it's
crossed four hours now. Maybe I should
stop now. My throat is protesting. But
anyway, thank you so much, sir. Thank
you so much. Ankura says, "How can we
stop ourselves from becoming a vasal?"
How can we stop ourselves from becoming
a vasal? By becoming more powerful. That
is the only solution. By becoming more
powerful and having more options.
So, one of the options we need to have
is our own sources of oil and gas. If we
can discover miraculously sources of oil
and gas which can provide for all our
needs, that gives us tremendous
advantages and leverage. That's one
thing. The other thing is become more
powerful, become a larger economy,
become a more powerful military, all of
those things. That's how you stop
yourself. And also, of course, aligning
yourself with like-minded nations, other
nations if we can. That's how you stop
yourself from becoming a vasal. It's
always by having more leverage and more
options.
And that brings me finally to the end of
this live stream.
All right, I shall end it over here.
Thank you so much everybody for all the
questions. It's been a very long one
today, more than 4 hours, but it's a
privilege to be able to do this with you
all. So, thank you so much everyone and
I'll see you in next week's live
streams. Until then, take care, keep
asking questions, keep learning, and
keep raising your standards. I'll see
you next week. Bye-bye.